<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Pxtl.ca</title><subtitle type="text">Pxtl.ca</subtitle><id>http://www.pxtl.ca/</id><updated>2020-10-12T16:00:07-04:00</updated><author><name>Martin Zarate</name><uri>http://www.pxtl.ca</uri><email>pxtl@hotmail.com</email></author><generator>Sandra.Snow Atom Generator</generator><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.pxtl.ca/feed.xml" /><link rel="self" type="text/html" title="Pxtl.ca" href="http://www.pxtl.ca/feed.xml" /><entry><id>http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/10/10/integrity-commissioner/</id><title type="text">Council and the Integrity Commissioner</title><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Okay, so let me just make sure I'm getting the latest City of Hamilton council
misadventure straight.  It's been hard to keep track of this overlaid in all the
pandemic pandemonium.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;edit (2020-10-12)&lt;/strong&gt;: Thanks to Ryan McGreal for helping me out with some details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cameron Kroetsch is a local activist who is an unpaid volunteer on the city's
LGBT advisory committee.  He's butt heads with the city before, like when said
the city shouldn't fly the rainbow flag during Pride because they hadn't really
stood up for the city's LGBT community properly. This attitude of his was
vindicated when the police failed to protect the Gage park pride event from
violent homophobic activists, despite (according to Kroetsch) having been
specifically told exactly where and when to be.  The police defend this because
Pride's leadership had asked the police not to patrol the interior of the event
or set up a recruiting table (the violence was on the edge of the park).&lt;/p&gt;

</summary><published>2020-10-10T04:00:00Z</published><updated>2020-10-10T04:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/10/10/integrity-commissioner/" /><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Okay, so let me just make sure I'm getting the latest City of Hamilton council
misadventure straight.  It's been hard to keep track of this overlaid in all the
pandemic pandemonium.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;edit (2020-10-12)&lt;/strong&gt;: Thanks to Ryan McGreal for helping me out with some details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cameron Kroetsch is a local activist who is an unpaid volunteer on the city's
LGBT advisory committee.  He's butt heads with the city before, like when said
the city shouldn't fly the rainbow flag during Pride because they hadn't really
stood up for the city's LGBT community properly. This attitude of his was
vindicated when the police failed to protect the Gage park pride event from
violent homophobic activists, despite (according to Kroetsch) having been
specifically told exactly where and when to be.  The police defend this because
Pride's leadership had asked the police not to patrol the interior of the event
or set up a recruiting table (the violence was on the edge of the park).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Mr. Kroetsch has established that he's willing to fight city hall, for
apparently good reasons. Then you've got the Integrity Commissioner, a lawyer
appointed and paid by council, who is ostensibly supposed to monitor council
misbehavior.  Dozens of reports of such misbehavior have happened, such as
Whitehead browbeating people on and off the council floor, and Merulla using his
office to threaten a woman over a slow shipment... and none of these complaints
rose to needing a report before council.  The I.C. had very little to say when
Councillor Ferguson shoved local independent journalist Joey Coleman after a
heated council session, which can be considered assault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there are other goings on, like that a known neo-Nazi leader was working in
the city hall I.T. department and therefore having access to an incredible
amount of sensitive info (he has since been let go).  His position was
apparenlty kept hidden from the public Org Chart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And like all cities right now, hard questions are being asked about the role of
policing and civilian oversight, especially with the apparent police disinterest
in going after far-right groups such as the yellow-vesters that regularly
protested on the forecourt, even illegally driving a bus into the space. And
finally, a fissure exists between the old, more conservative side of council and
the new, fresher faces on council that are supported by the city's
actively-engaged public activists, with the Mayor desperately trying to be the
dispassionate peacemaker he always is.  Councillor Merulla sees these new
councillors as an NDP-backed "cabal" (one of the three new councillors
previously ran for the NDP). So, with this stage set: Kroetsch penned a motion
in the LGBT Advisory Committee describing the two related problems: that a known
white supremacist extremist was working in city hall, and that an ex-cop had
been appointed to a civilian oversight component of the police board, defeating
the purpose of the oversight.  The motion, which said that City Hall should not
fly the Pride flag, was passed by the LGBT Advisory Committee.  No names were
included in the motion. However, both of these facts were very embarrassing to
city staff. The clerk told Kroetsch &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to release the document to the public
because it contained private info, and he sent it anyways. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mkuplens/status/1311673941790949378"&gt;Details of the
document and the redactions are here (thanks Martin
Kuplēns-Ewart)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-10-10-integrity-commissioner/Kroetsch-letter-censored-and-original.jpg" alt="image of Kroetsch document comparing redactions" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As described in the Twitter thread, looking at the contents of this document, and
the redacted form that the clerk released, I don't see any private information.
Instead, what I see is embarrassing information.  And given the city's
established history of covering up embarrassments like the Red Hill asphalt
report that described slippery conditions that may have led to multiple deaths,
and the report that a sewage valve had accidentally been left open releasing
a river of sewage into Cootes Paradise, the pattern is obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the redactions are pointless since the City itself had published a fully
unredacted version of the motion (complete with names) on the City website,
which is why he disagreed with the Clerk's opposition to him publishing the
redacted version (she wanted an even more redacted version). The I.C. declined to
include this information in the final report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And suddenly the Integrity Commissioner's role has silently been expanded to
cover committees, not just council, with no apparent justification or
documentation of this change.  And then instead of the dozens of complaints
against council-members, a complaint against Kroetsch jumps the queue.  On the
council floor, the claim is that Kroetsch ignored an order from the clerk to
respect privacy and not issue the document... but the redactions to the document
don't contain PII, they contain &lt;em&gt;embarrassments&lt;/em&gt;.  And one of these elements in
the document contained an active warning to an at-risk community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And meanwhile, the police services site listed the very same information - that
an ex-officer was being appointed to this oversight group.  Obviously, context
is everything - it's fine for an ex-cop to be welcomed into a board, as long as
you don't point out that this might be a bad idea. And so the IC agreed with the
clerk, and Council bought the story that Kroetsch should have taken the
obviously-incorrect order from the Clerk, and not sent the document.  And so
council supports the report blaming Kroetsch.  No real consequences, but a
gesture showing that his actions are unacceptable.  Even the new Councillors
support the motion, because Kroetsch went against the clerk, and they don't want
advisory committees doing that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, in the wake of that decision, Councillor Whitehead is threatening other
advisory committees with the attentions of the Integrity Commissioner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as if that isn't enough, we have the Mayor now going directly to the
Premier to fight for the controversial Commonwealth Games without council
direction to do so.  Isn't this exactly the kind of oversight and guidance the
I.C. is supposed to respond to?  But again the I.C. says nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in the midst of all this, the mayor is saying that this is all fine.  That,
in all of this lunacy, this council really isn't any worse than its
predecessors.  Everything Is Fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of all this, I'm sending the following letter to council:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;My letter&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hamilton City Councilmembers,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With COVID and Trump dominating the news, it's difficult to keep track of
Council goings-on, but what I've heard about council and the integrity
commissioner is very concerning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the civilian oversight of the police board was being undermined, and a
known white nationalist extremist leader was working at city hall, Cameron
Kroetsch tried to inform the public of legitimate serious concerns, in a fashion
that, examining the document, is very respectful of privacy. The same
information was publicized freely elsewhere, and in greater detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-10-10-integrity-commissioner/Kroetsch-letter-censored-and-original.jpg" alt="image of Kroetsch document comparing redactions" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reviewing the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mkuplens/status/1311673941790949378"&gt;details of the document and the redactions here (thanks
Martin Kuplēns-Ewart)&lt;/a&gt;,
it is impossible to interpret the clerk's actions anything but a cover-up,
rather than a responsible attempt to redact P.I.I. that was not present in the
document, but was already available on the city's own website! And this council
has already been plagued by multiple embarrassing cover-ups. But instead of
reaffirming a commitment to transparency, we instead see the council abusing the
role of the I.C.'s office to silence him? How is there no interest in trying to
be better? After everything that's happened, I'd think that council would make
at least a cursory effort to be above reproach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how you may feel about Mr. Kroetsch, it seems impossible to
reasonably see him in the wrong on this. And yet, Council abruptly expanded the
role of the I.C. to cover non-councilmembers and then the case of Mr. Kroetsch
jumped the queue over numerous legitimate claims against councilmembers (and
anybody who follows the Council news on even a cursory basis knows there are
many numerous legitimate complaints about councilmembers' ethics). What is the
last line of defense here? What is the responsible way to disclose this
information, to protect the Hamiltonian public? Because if council is more
committed to cover-ups than justice and community safety, and the clerk and the
I.C. are committed to supporting them, then it looks from the outside like the
entire tree is rotten, and Mr. Kroetsch did the exact right thing in ignoring an
absurd instruction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The I.C. is being used to remove a pesky thorn from the side of council. This is
blatantly political.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, when the kind of action that is supposed to draw the attention of the
I.C. happens, what do we hear? Examples are endless, but the most recent event
is the mayor going to the Premiere to fight for the controversial Commonwealth
games bid without council direction. Why do we even have an Integrity
Commissioner if the office is simply going to be used as a mouthpiece for
council?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now councillor Whitehead is using the I.C. to threaten the HCCI - completely
brazenly, in public, on Twitter! This is the culture of total impunity you've
all created. I hope you're proud of yourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This term of council has been intensely disappointing because even
councilmembers and a mayor I used to have a great deal of respect for have let
us all down. Even the councilmembers I didn't really agree with, I appreciated
the diversity of perspectives they brought to council. I can only hope that, at
least for some members of council, that this was a rash decision where they were
not in full possession of the facts of the case at the time of their vote to
support the I.G.'s report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say it ain't so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin Zarate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hamilton Ward 1 Constituent&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/09/26/covid-cocktails-2/</id><title type="text">Covid Cocktails 2</title><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Continuing on from my previous round, I've done another 14 days of cocktails.
This time it's a more '70s theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/Covid-cocktails-2-collage-1024.jpg" alt="Covid cocktails 2 collage" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</summary><published>2020-09-26T04:00:00Z</published><updated>2020-09-26T04:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/09/26/covid-cocktails-2/" /><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Continuing on from my previous round, I've done another 14 days of cocktails.
This time it's a more '70s theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/Covid-cocktails-2-collage-1024.jpg" alt="Covid cocktails 2 collage" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;14 Days of Cocktails&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;California Root Beer&lt;/strong&gt; - this is a '70s drink with a zillion variations
(the California is generally with club soda, the Bartender's Root Beer generally
with coke - it was plenty sweet, I wouldn't want it with coke)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://noseychef.com/2018/02/16/california-root-beer/"&gt;https://noseychef.com/2018/02/16/california-root-beer/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.33 oz vodka &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.66 oz Kahlúa &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz Galliano &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soda  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/California-root-beer.jpg" alt="California root beer" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It tasted great, but it was tricky to measure 2/3 of an ounce on my shot glass,
so I probably went way high, because it tasted of too much Kahlua. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, the Galliano already has a pretty strong root beer flavor, I'd think
going down to half an ounce of Kahlua would be better - I suspect the only
reason it calls for so much is for colour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Algonquin&lt;/strong&gt;, which is named for a hotel in NYC, not the park. Recipe calls for
Bianco (semi-sweet) vermouth, but I used red (sweet) vermouth.  Also, orange
bitters instead of creole.  Both because that's what I have.  Yeah, I know I
said no more substitutions, but these are smaller ones. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't know if this was too far from the real McCoy, but it's tasty. &lt;a href="https://diffordsguide.com/cocktails/recipe/41/algonquin"&gt;Original
recipe is here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My version of it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 oz rye&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.75 oz pineapple juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.75 oz sweet vermouth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dash orange bitters &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shaken with ice.  I had mine on the rocks because I like my rye that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/Algonquin.jpg" alt="Algonquin" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really liked this.  The raisin-y vermouth marries well to the pineapple and
they both play off the rye flavours well.  It's not super boozy a but it's also
not a candy umbrella drink.  It feels like a Manhattan done right to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;White Russian&lt;/strong&gt;.  I mixed it light:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.75oz Kahlua &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5oz vodka&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.75oz half-and-half cream (I literally mixed half milk half cream)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build in a glass, present unmixed, then mix. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/white-Russian.jpg" alt="White Russian" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dude abides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tasty as hell, but it's a brute force approach: overpowering the alcohol flavors
with sweetness and fat and coffee flavors.  That's kind of a theme of '70s
cocktails, but I can't argue with the results. Scrumptious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unnamed supermodel walks into a bar and says "I want something that will wake me
up and f&lt;em&gt;*&lt;/em&gt; me up."  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus the &lt;strong&gt;espresso martini&lt;/strong&gt; was born. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 oz vodka &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5oz Kahlua &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5oz Moka-pot coffee made from espresso beans (don't have an espresso maker) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5oz simple syrup &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lemon peel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All ingredients go into a shaker with lots of ice.  Shake vigorously until cold,
strain into cocktail glass.  Garnish with 3 espresso beans.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/espresso-martini.jpg" alt="Espresso martini" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Model Who Was Possibly Kate Moss' description was accurate.  It's also pretty
tasty in that 70s brute-force way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How to Drink vid for espresso martini&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dtQeGJlOFyM" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gin and It&lt;/strong&gt;.  Which is really just a traditional sweet martini that we fancy
up a bit (the It is short for "Italian Vermouth". The recipes online run the
gamut but roughly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5oz gin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.75oz sweet vermouth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;N dashes orange bitters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clementine slice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really just saw a pic of one with an orange slice in it and decided to go
orangey on it. Wierd, complex drink, but it definitely got the wheels turning
with its flavours.  The gin quiets the sweet vermouth a bit, and the hint of
sweetness and orange work well. Want moar orange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/gin-and-it.jpg" alt="Gin and it" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside, I'm not sure if Dillon's Orange bitters is really mild or that's just
normal for orange bitters, but I find I have to go nuts with that stuff in order
to get a satisfying hint of its flavour.  It's really subtle compared to the
Angostura.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After yesterday's orangey drink I wanted more, so I bought the triple sec I
craved. The only triple sec they had was Cointreau, which is expensive but
lovely. Back in my undergrad triple sec was a floormate's "yes, we'll drink
shots of this because we're 20 and that's a thing 20-year-olds do" and in
hindsight that's a waste of a fancy liqueur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had no idea of any cocktails to make with it, so I winged it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I give you the &lt;strong&gt;Orange Old Fashioned&lt;/strong&gt;.  I free poured it into a glass, so all
quantities are guesses:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5oz rye (Crown Royal Harvest)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.75oz cointreau triple sec &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5oz simple syrup &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 dashes orange bitters  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Half a Clementine cut in wedges &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/orange-old-fashioned.jpg" alt="Orange old fashioned" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was exactly the drink I wanted in that moment.  Icy and tangy and sweet and
mixed perfectly with the warm sour/spicy flavors of the rye.  I'd had a super
frustrating day and this was the perfect thing for it.  Like an orange
poundcake, chilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That ruby-red vodka cooler from Sex and the City - the &lt;strong&gt;Cosmopolitan&lt;/strong&gt;!  ...  Turns
out it's not ruby red or a cooler.  It's cloudy and pink and not nearly as sweet
as I expected. Seriously, I'm using the Difford's recipe:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz vodka (cheated, no Citron here) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz triple sec &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 oz cranberry cocktail &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5 oz lime juice &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dash orange bitters  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shaken with ice, pour in cocktail glass.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.diffordsguide.com/cocktails/recipe/472/cosmopolitan-cocktail-diffords-recipe"&gt;https://www.diffordsguide.com/cocktails/recipe/472/cosmopolitan-cocktail-diffords-recipe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.5oz isn't much cranberry cocktail at all.  I'd expected more overpowering
sweet cranberry flavor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/cosmopolitan.jpg" alt="Cosmopolitan" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I needed stronger cranberry cocktail to make it sweeter and redder?
Either way, its flavor was surprisingly complex.  The lime and orange and
cranberry kind of blended together in a way where I couldn't pick any of them
out.  My wife loved it, I was mostly... confused?  I mean it was a fine drink,
like halfway between a vodka martini and a sour.  I just couldn't get past how
far it was from what I expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;White Lady&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5oz gin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.75oz triple sec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.75oz lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.33oz simple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 egg white  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shake dry, then shake with ice.  Except I forgot the dry shake so it looked
wonky instead of clean head I got on the whiskey sour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall... I think I preferred the regular whiskey sour.  I'm just not seeing
what the switch to gin gets me here.  I mean, the Cointreau is always nice, but
it's pretty muted in this drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/white-lady.jpg" alt="White lady" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I made some &lt;strong&gt;blender piña colada&lt;/strong&gt; too (double whammy day!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3rd of a can of coconut milk (leftover from dinner)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 cups of frozen pineapples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a few splashes of pineapple juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and blend.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Throw candied cherries on top because candied cherries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add rum for adults as needed  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple and tasty.  Pic below is the kids' drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/blender-pina-colada.jpg" alt="blender piña colada" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Syrups&lt;/strong&gt;. The basic cocktail syrups are simple syrup, demerara syrup,
grenadine, and orgeat. Two are trivial to make: boil a cup of water and add
between 1 and 2 cups sugar, mix till dissolved, then bottle. White sugar for
simple, demerara for demerara.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://jeffreymorgenthaler.com/how-to-make-your-own-grenadine/"&gt;https://jeffreymorgenthaler.com/how-to-make-your-own-grenadine/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grenadine is more complicated because of disagreement about what it is. Modern
grenadine is vaguely fruit flavored corn syrup with bright red colouring.
Traditional grenadine is pomegranate syrup. I used Jeffrey Morgenthaler's
recipe, by way of How To Drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/syrups.jpg" alt="syrups" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note I used the h2d approach that bottled juice is fine and boiling is okay.
The how to drink recipe vid is here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qTF7QkIkns8" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pomegranate juice, pomegranate concentrate, orange flower water, and sugar.
&lt;a href="https://www.piconefinefood.ca/"&gt;Picone Fine Foods&lt;/a&gt; was my go-to for these more
obscure ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and on orgeat, the other main syrup?  It sounds super complicated so I'm just
going to buy some. Finally, made a virgin cocktail for my girls - an orange Good
Morning Sunburst, but skipping freezing the OJ because who has the time? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 cup OJ &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;half minican club soda (recipe called for full but glass was full)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz grenadine &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5 oz simple syrup  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a drop vanilla&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theworktop.com/breakfast-brunch-recipes/orange-juice-brunch-mocktail/"&gt;https://www.theworktop.com/breakfast-brunch-recipes/orange-juice-brunch-mocktail/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/morning-sunburst.jpg" alt="morning sunburst" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(the recipe called for vanilla syrup so I ratio'd it down to the
half-shot-plus-drop approach). Presented to my daughters then stirred.  Older
one said it was too sweet. Younger said it tastes like caramel and rated it
"double chef's kiss"  Probably should have cut back on something to do the full
club soda minican to water-down the syrups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hamiltonnews.com/news-story/10189177-hamilton-coun-john-paul-danko-ejects-coun-terry-whitehead-from-contentious-meeting/"&gt;On September 11th, 2020, Hamilton Ward 8 Councillor John-Paul Danko ejected the
ever-insulting councillor Whitehead from a council meeting for inappropriate
conduct and refusing to
apologize&lt;/a&gt;.
This was long, long overdue.  In honour of Jon-Paul Danko's leadership in
council - a &lt;strong&gt;Ward Eight&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 oz whiskey (Wiser's Special Blend) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5 oz fresh squeeze lemon juice &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5 oz OJ &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5 oz pomegranate grenadine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cocktail cherries for garnish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shake with ice, pour to chilled cocktail glass, garnish with cocktail cherries
It's actually my 2nd attempt at Ward 8, I wanted to get this right.  Following
the canonical recipe yesterday - well, Greg from H2D tried similar and said it
"tastes like feet".  I didn't like it either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WhA46H6fOzA" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pic of my first attempt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/ward-eight-first-attempt.jpg" alt="ward eight, first attempt" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Googling around I found other rebalanced recipes, and yes, it's much better with
the citrus cut back and more grenadine.  Also using Wiser's Special Blend, which
is more mixy, instead of CR Harvest Rye which is super-rye-forwards - this was a
big improvement.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like just tweaking the fruit quantities isn't full out cheating - this is
still a Ward 8, but definitely a more pleasant drink than the canonical version
(which as more orange/lemon and only a few barspoons of grenadine).  Also, the
drink calls for rye instead of a blended whiskey (although my cheap Wiser's
Special Blend &lt;em&gt;says&lt;/em&gt; it's a rye, I don't think it actually counts).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pic of my successful version:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/ward-eight.jpg" alt="ward eight" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Came out a complex and tasty citrus/pom whiskey sour.  Enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 11&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shirley Temple&lt;/strong&gt; (and the &lt;strong&gt;Dirty Shirley&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz pomegranate grenadine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 oz ginger ale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(optional) 2 oz vodka for "dirty" &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build in a Collins glass full of ice, stir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/Shirley-Temple.jpg" alt="Shirley Temple" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy to make, easy to drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife liked it, my girls liked it, apparently the only person who hates these
was Shirley Temple herself, who thought the drink too sweet and didn't
appreciate people fabricating her endorsement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's sweet fizzy pom ginger ale. Nothing to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 12&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lemon Drop&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2oz vodka&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz simple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz fresh lemon juice &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5 oz triple sec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plate of sugar &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wipe lemon-half around cocktail glass and roll in sugar to rim. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fill shaker with ice and liquid ingredients, shake.  Pour into glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/lemon-drop.jpg" alt="lemon drop" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a hit.  It's super sweet - like lemon candy - but the citrus flavors
still shine.  So. Much. Sugar.  Also lots of alcohol, so I don't recommend
drinking a lot of those - it'd be a hangover in a glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 13&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We're back to the '70s again with a &lt;strong&gt;Golden Dream&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 oz Galliano L'Autentico&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 oz Cointreau&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 oz orange juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.75 oz cream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shaken with ice, pour to a chilled cocktail glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/golden-dream.jpg" alt="golden dream" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really liked this cocktail.  I mean, it's definitely too sweet, but I'm
impressed how it tastes so much like custard - custard and orange.  The orange
works great with the alcohol and the custard flavors.  Incredibly easy to drink.
Amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 14&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ramos Gin Fizz. I'm going to take a break from daily cocktails for a bit, so I'm
ending with a bang. In a shaker, no ice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2oz gin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.75oz lemon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.75oz lime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5oz simple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1oz cream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 egg white&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 drops orange flower water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, club soda we'll need later. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dry shake (no ice) in the shaker for a bit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then add ice to the shaker and shake like a fiend until it feels like your arms
are going to fall off. Pour filtered into an empty Collins glass, then add club
soda to make the foam insane and so thick you can stand up a metal straw in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember being a kid and being confused why people thought too much foam is a
bad thing - a big head of foam just seemed so &lt;em&gt;neat&lt;/em&gt;.  If you were that kid too,
this is the drink for you.  Over half the glass is drinkable lemon-lime
expanding insulation.  This drink is &lt;em&gt;wierd&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flavor-wise, it's a mildly-sweetened creamy gin sour.  The hint of floral taste
from the orange blossom water (also used to make grenadine) gives it a touch of
the alien that matches up with its appearance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-26-Covid-cocktails-2/Ramos-gin-fizz.jpg" alt="Ramos gin fizz" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that's my finale.  I'm going to take a break from daily cocktails for my
health and see if I can get back into running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside: I finally picked up a citrus squeezer - I'd been skooshing lemons and
limes by hand until now.  So obviously I'm not &lt;em&gt;done&lt;/em&gt; done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How to Drink vid of Ramos gin fizz&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YHRg3iCuwzw" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Final thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First day of running &lt;em&gt;sucked&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, now that I have a decent inventory of liquors and liqueurs it didn't take
nearly as much research to hunt down recipes that I could make.  I get antsy
about inventory with things... I hate taking up space with untidy stuff.  Spent
too long cleaning up a generation of knick-knacks and unfinished projects, and
so I don't like leaving messes.  So I'm trying to use up some of my bottles and
just working with the recipes I already know. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been making gin slings for myself fairly often, and various soda mixes for
the kids.  They like the novelty of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm still deciding where to go next for when I start up again.  I still haven't
touched the whole tequila/mezcal side of the world of liquors, ditto
brandies/cognac.  Also, if I can get my hands on some orgeat or raspberry
liqueur that should open up some new doors too.  The trick is that I've been
trying to avoid cheap syrups that mostly just add sugar to the drink.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/09/09/covid-cocktails/</id><title type="text">Covid Cocktails</title><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So thanks to watching too many "How to Drink" Youtube videos, I've gotten into
mixing cocktails.  We're all drinking at home anyways, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I made approximately one cocktail per day, mostly things I've never tried
before.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary><published>2020-09-09T04:00:00Z</published><updated>2020-09-09T04:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/09/09/covid-cocktails/" /><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So thanks to watching too many "How to Drink" Youtube videos, I've gotten into
mixing cocktails.  We're all drinking at home anyways, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I made approximately one cocktail per day, mostly things I've never tried
before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On cocktails, goals, and fun: In a pause on my exploration in mixing drinks,
some notes:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anything worth doing is worth making goals about, even your fun. If I don't
plan my fun, I'll spend all day doom-scrolling Twitter, or 4AM Civ. I've
kicked a bad Reddit habit many times - in the sense that "quitting smoking is
easy, I've done it lots of times".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, my goal was 2 weeks, 1 new cocktail per day.  I fell a bit short but I
still feel like I learned a lot (don't buy things that don't come in small
bottles, don't do substitutions), had some fun, and made some tasty things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I agree with Greg from How To Drink: sours are a great place to start. All
you need is a shaker, a spirit, a citrus fruit, and DIY simple syrup. Don't
go nuts buying yourself a liquor cabinet full of white elephants and tools
you'll never use. Cobbler shakers are &lt;em&gt;fine&lt;/em&gt;.  You can even squeeze lime into
a shot-glass by hand in a pinch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm just enjoying picking a direction and advancing slowly. I started with
Greg's pre-prohibition drinks and now I'm planning on exploring more the '70s
party things - lots of coffee, chocolate, vanilla, mint flavors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you're already a whiskey drinker, an Old Fashioned is an easy upgrade. Try
it. Angostura aromatic bitters are available in every grocery store and are
basically a spice-mix for cocktails, go get some.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you're a gin drinker: get some Rose's Lime Cordial.  Gimlet.  OMG.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What follows is my detailed 12 days of notes on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The 12 Days of Cocktails&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 1 cocktail was a traditional Cuban-style daiquiri&lt;/strong&gt; for my wife. No
blender. Lime, rum, and simple syrup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holy crap nobody told me how good fresh-squeezed lime tastes.  I even cheated
and used a flavorful Jamaican rum instead of a simple white one. Amazing.
Seriously, why didn't you people tell me that fresh lime juice with a little
sugar tastes so amazing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relevant "How To Drink" video: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q_b7xow1Ck4" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other day 1 cocktail was a nice &lt;strong&gt;old fashioned&lt;/strong&gt;. I used my fave Crown Royal
rye, which has powerful flavor... I used Greg's cheat (Greg is the How to Drink
guy) of simple syrup &amp;amp; dash of aromatic bitters instead of bitters-soaked
sugar... I was like "this tastes like sweetened rye".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I added a few more dashes of bitters.  Wow.  Makes all the difference,
great drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, garnished with Tillen Farms Bada Bing cocktail cherries because I'm too
damned cheap for Luxardos, and I'm not eating those gross maraschino cherries.
Tasty.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An old fashioned is a fun easy upgrade for a rye drinker.  Strongly recommend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other "How To Drink" video:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DLk67oMq8Og" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 2 of COVID cocktails: &lt;strong&gt;the Manhattan&lt;/strong&gt;.  Because I bought the wrong kind of
vermouth by accident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How To Drink vid:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MFs4hA2DriU" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crown Royal rye, Dillon's sweet vermouth, and some bitters and a cherry.  This
was... less successful.  Wife found it vile.  Seemed like a waste of good rye
for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worse yet, now I have a 750ml bottle of sweet vermouth and no idea what to do
with it. The stuff only keeps a month so I've got to use it or lose it. Sweet
Vermouth tastes like wrong icewine straight... it might be good with club soda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 3 of COVID Cocktails: &lt;strong&gt;the Bees Knees&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a prohibition-era sour.
I'm using the How To Drink recipe, which is different and simpler from some
versions I've seen online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 oz London dry gin (I used Tanqueray), &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz fresh lemon juice,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz honey syrup. 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Honey syrup = equal parts thick honey and water, boiled.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Served shaken in a cocktail glass.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I just garnished with a lemon wheel.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I went a bit heavier on the honey syrup and I don't regret it at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like all sours, this was a hit.  Made for both me and wife, it's an interesting
drink - no matter how well I shake it, the honey flavor comes and goes as if
it's settling in different parts of the drink.  The gin flavors don't &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt;
disappear, but they're subtle against lemon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm going to admit: I ran out of fresh lemon halfway through the 2nd drink and
used bottled lemon juice... and honestly can't tell the difference.  I guess my
palette is crap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How To Drink:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3Zik8fgGUOg" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Days 4 and 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Days 4 and 5 of Covid Cocktails (I've been blogging 2 days behind, this is a
good time to catch up): revisiting Dillon's sweet vermouth. I've switched out my
flavourful CR Harvest Rye with a more mixable J.P.Wiser's "Special Blend" (I'm
trying to buy Canadian).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, day 4 was &lt;strong&gt;Manhattan round 2&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so the Wisers blend is much milder and works better with the taste of the
sweet vermouth for the Manhattan... still not loving it.  There's still a
strangeness to the flavor of the vermouth that just doesn't work for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 5 was &lt;strong&gt;Sweet Vermouth Spritz&lt;/strong&gt;.  Just pour a pile of ice into a tall glass,
2 oz vermouth, 4 oz club soda.  Built in the glass and stirred with a bar-spoon.
I know it doesn't really count as a cocktail since it's just liquor and soda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this... this actually works for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sweet vermouth still tastes like Wrong Ice-wine to me, and that strangeness
still hits me with the first sip, but I was enjoying it by halfway down the
glass.  I think spritzes and the like are the future of that bottle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also marks the point where I'm not just doing cocktails from How To Drink
but instead going out and researching "hey, I'd like to try that".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 6 of COVID cocktails: &lt;strong&gt;Gin Sling&lt;/strong&gt;!... with vermouth - some recipes call
for the vermouth, some don't.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full recipe
&lt;a href="https://www.thespruceeats.com/classic-gin-sling-cocktail-recipe-760084"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
- 1.5 oz gin
- 1 oz sweet vermouth
- 3/4 oz lemon juice
- 1 oz simple syrup
- Dash Angostura Bitters
- 3-4 oz club soda
- Garnish: lemon peel
- Ice &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-09-Covid-cocktails/gin-sling.jpg" alt="gin sling picture" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build in shaker everything but the club soda over ice, fill glass with more ice,
strain from shaker to glass, fill to top with club soda. This tasted &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt;.
Nice mix of sweet pound-backable drink and complex flavors. Although I misread
the recipe and skimped on the soda. My pic is missing the garnish because wifey
saw the peel on the cutting board and mistook for waste, so it got binned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yay, vermouth!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What's funny is that I've had a sling before... A Singapore Sling while I was at
a work trip in Singapore.  That was an umbrella drink that builds an incredibly
complex series of flavors and then obliterates them with endless sugar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was simpler and I like it a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 7 of COVID Cocktails: we introduce a new ingredient, Galliano L'autentico,
and leave behind the pre-prohibition drinks for the '70s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yup, I made my wife a &lt;strong&gt;Harvey Wallbanger&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was tasty!  I got that creamsicle flavor and she loved it. ... but yeah, I
didn't fill the glass well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-09-Covid-cocktails/Harvey-Wallbanger.jpg" alt="Harvey Wallbanger
picture" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.diffordsguide.com/cocktails/recipe/936/harvey-wallbanger"&gt;https://www.diffordsguide.com/cocktails/recipe/936/harvey-wallbanger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 8's Covid Cocktail was the &lt;strong&gt;Gimlet&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Equal parts Tanqueray gin and Rose's Lime Cordial.  Fun little drink - sweet but
not too sweet, an explosion of bitter and sour lime flavors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-09-Covid-cocktails/gimlet.jpg" alt="gimlet picture" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How To Drink:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iVC64ad8SMs" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 9 of COVID Cocktails... I wanted to get creative - building the Difford's
guide "&lt;strong&gt;Key Lime Pie #3&lt;/strong&gt;" but with some substitutions based on ingredient
availability. &lt;a href="https://www.diffordsguide.com/cocktails/recipe/1103/key-lime-pie-3"&gt;https://www.diffordsguide.com/cocktails/recipe/1103/key-lime-pie-3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I did&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 oz vodka&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz Galliano L'autentico&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 oz pineapple juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5 oz lime juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5 oz lime cordial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rimmed glass with brown sugar (supposed to be crushed graham crackers, this is
a substitution)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-09-Covid-cocktails/key-lime-pie.jpg" alt="key lime pie picture" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big switch was replacing vanilla liqueur (and some vodka) with Galliano,
which has vanilla and licorice flavors in it and I really fell in love with it
in the Wallbanger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn't what I'd hoped. The gimlet made me love lime cordial, so I overused it
here, especially since it combines with the bitter notes of Galliano to
over-bitter what should be a confection.  I was really hoping for the vanilla of
the Galliano to shine through here, but they got kind of lost.  It tasted like a
bitter lime vodka sour.  Which is fine, but not what I was going for. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, rimming a glass is harder than I expected, especially with clumpy brown
sugar, but I've never rimmed a glass before.  Too much lime juice, I think. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Lindsey loved it!  So I should take my victories where I find them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 10 of COVID Cocktails: the &lt;strong&gt;whiskey sour&lt;/strong&gt;... I'd been scared to make this
because of the raw egg white... worth the risk.  Sooooo goooood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used Greg from How To Drink's recipe for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz simple syrup (mine is 1:1 so milder than Greg's)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 egg white&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 oz whiskey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dry shake 10 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shake with ice 15 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dash of angostura bitters in the foam, mixed in with a toothpick.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-09-Covid-cocktails/whiskey-sour.jpg" alt="whiskey sour picture" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I overshook it because it was all fizz until it settled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The taste was heavenly.  Wifey turned up her nose at it between the bitters and
the egg white.  Her loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(HTD vid is already upthread for the daiquiri)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 11&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 11 COVID cocktail: a nice boring &lt;strong&gt;Tom Collins&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1oz lemon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5oz 1:1 simple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 oz gin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shake with ice, pour over ice, fill to the top of the glass with club soda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-09-Covid-cocktails/Tom-Collins.jpg" alt="Tom Collins" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;... it was fine, I guess?  I found it kind of bland.  Had to stir it up just to
get passed the club soda. Drank it about a third of the way down, said "screw
this" and added syrup and orange bitters. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I used too much club soda, I dunno.  Or maybe if I had a gin I liked
better than Tanqueray, which is fine but its flavors aren't that great to taste
diluted with lemon and a splash of sugar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTD:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bK_kBsqqA0I" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 12&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 12 of COVID Cocktails, we return to the '70s with another Galliano drink,
the &lt;strong&gt;Golden Cadillac&lt;/strong&gt;.  And again, Martin re-learns that he doesn't know enough
about mixology to do substitutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Equal parts cream, creme de cacao, and galliano L'autentico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-09-09-Covid-cocktails/golden-Cadillac.jpg" alt="golden Cadillac picture" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, 360 double-chocolate vodka is not creme de cacao, and I am an idiot
for thinking otherwise.  It is a chocolate nuke that obliterates all other
flavors... Which is why I like it and have it in my cabinet, but it fails here.
I couldn't taste the Galliano, or even the cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, though, I won't be attempting this again even if I pick up creme de
cacao.  With nothing to add color or layers, it looks like milk.  You shave
chocolate on top just to make it look more like a cocktail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My favourites, overall&lt;/strong&gt;: Obviously, the Old Fashioned and the Gimlet, as
above - but the Old Fashioned is more a treat for somebody who's already a
whiskey-drinker.  The Whiskey Sour blew my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special mention goes to the Gin Sling that turned me around on the red vermouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lindsey's favourites were the Harvey Wallbanger and the Cuban Daiquiri (which is
technically just a Daiquiri, but there are two very different drinks bearing
that name).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah, it's been fun so far.  Before this I was mostly a beer drinker, with
the occasional emergency whiskey.  Nice to try something new.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/06/16/saving-uranus/</id><title type="text">Saving Uranus</title><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I'm finally getting myself a new computer.  Had it all figured out - new
off-lease desktops were coming available for my kids, and I was going to buy
myself a brand-new gaming machine.  No hard feelings because everybody's getting
a new machine at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just had to wait until August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is why it's awesome that my kids' computer (named Uranus) died.  And died in an
infuriating way - it was murdered by its own software.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary><published>2020-06-16T04:00:00Z</published><updated>2020-06-16T04:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/06/16/saving-uranus/" /><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I'm finally getting myself a new computer.  Had it all figured out - new
off-lease desktops were coming available for my kids, and I was going to buy
myself a brand-new gaming machine.  No hard feelings because everybody's getting
a new machine at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just had to wait until August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is why it's awesome that my kids' computer (named Uranus) died.  And died in an
infuriating way - it was murdered by its own software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, suddenly my son was upset that he couldn't open the shutdown menu.  Or
search the start menu.  On closer examination, the problem was pervasive -
couldn't open sub-menus in start, couldn't use the address bar in IE, couldn't
open uninstall dialogs in the add/remove program screen. Any new-windows-UI
screen that tried to create a floating widget failed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I went through the expected stack of approaches that every forum will rattle off:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sfc /scannow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dism (both variants)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;various built-in troubleshooters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;installing all updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;uninstalling recent updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a big crazy powershell scripts that reinstalls as much of the Universal
Windows Platform (UWP) apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;switching to other user profiles - each of my children have their own user
account and they all have this bug &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;turning off all startup programs in task manager restart with msconfig with
all non-microsoft services turned off &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;safe mode... which worked!  But you can't live in safe mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reinstall the OS (without removing software)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside, "answers.microsoft.com" should be renamed "questions" because there are a
lot of people asking things there and not a lot of answers besides "sfc
/scannow".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, this came down to "okay, let's reinstall windows".  Which sucked
because it meant sitting down with each of my kids and backing up their stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even that didn't work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pulled out all the stops.  I crawled through procmon and process explorer.  I
tried rolling back windows versions (couldn't do it).  So many infuriating
obstacles - the CD/DVD drive acted up, I couldn't boot from USB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, in a moment of frustration, I gave my PC a thump on the top.  And
that knocked the dvd out of its tray.  So it got scratched up, and I didn't even
have a windows DVD.  Did you know you can only burn the official windows ISOs to
dual-layer DVDs?  They're bigger than 4.7GB now.  Somehow, though, Windows Home
can burn images of itself, and they're smaller than 4.7GB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, I considered it a huge victory when I got it back to its old broken
state.  I think it was windows update 2004 that broke it, but I no longer care
enough to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that was my weekend.  The plus side is I'm getting a new computer so I can
hand-down my old one.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/05/30/mineclone2-skins/</id><title type="text">Mineclone2 Skins (rpi minetest-server part 4)</title><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Continuing on our marathon process of setting up the perfect Mineclone2 server,
this is going to be a brief side-guide - how set up skins in mineclone 2.  I
tried several approaches to this problem - the popular  skin mods in minetest
are meant to manage a connection to an online database of skins, and I just
wanted to pre-load enough skins so the kids would have a library to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn't get any of the existing skins mods to work fully, so we're going to
just set the files up manually.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary><published>2020-05-30T04:00:00Z</published><updated>2020-05-30T04:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/05/30/mineclone2-skins/" /><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Continuing on our marathon process of setting up the perfect Mineclone2 server,
this is going to be a brief side-guide - how set up skins in mineclone 2.  I
tried several approaches to this problem - the popular  skin mods in minetest
are meant to manage a connection to an online database of skins, and I just
wanted to pre-load enough skins so the kids would have a library to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn't get any of the existing skins mods to work fully, so we're going to
just set the files up manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The MineClone2 Skins Mod&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MineClone2 has a built-in skins mod (remember that minetest games are
collections of mods), but it only includes two skins by default. The skins are
located in the &lt;code&gt;mineclone2&lt;/code&gt; game folder under &lt;code&gt;mods/PLAYER/mcl_skins&lt;/code&gt;, so on our
Raspbian server it will be located at&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/var/games/minetest-server/.minetest/games/mineclone2/mods/PLAYER/mcl_skins
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the root folder for the minetest skins mod.  Each skin requires 2 files
and 1 optional file.  Each skin requires&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;textures/mcl_skins_character_N.png&lt;/code&gt; -- the actual skin file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;textures/mcl_skins_player_N.png&lt;/code&gt; -- the preview of the skin file that you'll see in the picker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;meta/mcl_skins_character_N.txt&lt;/code&gt; -- the text description of the skin (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where N is the skin's number.  The skins are sequentially numbered with no gaps -
so I had skins 1 through 94.  If you have a gap in the number mcl_skins will
stop searching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-05-30-Mineclone2-skins/files.jpg" alt="example files" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The meta txt file&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the three files is the meta text description of the skin.  It seems to only
ever contain 2 lines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;name = "Example_skin",
author = "exampleauthor",
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm a stickler for credit so I always included the author name, but the
MineClone2 skin picker didn't seem to show it anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The source&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mineclone2 skins are downloaded from the &lt;a href="http://minetest.fensta.bplaced.net/"&gt;skins
db&lt;/a&gt;. Pick the skins you like, download the
skin file and then rclick-save to download the thumbnail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The process&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So basically, our way to manually set up the skins is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) On the &lt;a href="http://minetest.fensta.bplaced.net/"&gt;skins website&lt;/a&gt;, download the
   skin and thumbnail of the skin you like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Rename the thumbnail and skin to match the mineclone2 skin-mod standard,
   being sure to copy out the part of the name that includes the author and
   skin-name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Create a meta txt file with the name and author as described above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Upload the files to your server and put them into the correct folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You shouldn't need to &lt;code&gt;chmod&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;chown&lt;/code&gt; anything because the minetest server users
only need to read the files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Next time&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Readdyyyy toooooo Mummmbbblle!&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/05/23/minetest-mods/</id><title type="text">Minetest Mods (rpi minetest-server part 3)</title><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Now that we've got our Minetest server built (see &lt;a href="http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/05/12/minetest-pi4-recipe/"&gt;previous
entry&lt;/a&gt; ), now it's time to learn how to
install mods and games into it, and how to run multiple instances of minetest.
In particular, we're going to be installing Mineclone 2.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary><published>2020-05-23T04:00:00Z</published><updated>2020-05-23T04:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/05/23/minetest-mods/" /><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Now that we've got our Minetest server built (see &lt;a href="http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/05/12/minetest-pi4-recipe/"&gt;previous
entry&lt;/a&gt; ), now it's time to learn how to
install mods and games into it, and how to run multiple instances of minetest.
In particular, we're going to be installing Mineclone 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Mods and Games in Minetest&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, you have to understand how minetest manages content.  Minetest has
two concepts: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mods&lt;/strong&gt;: small bits of code that will add one feature to a game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;games&lt;/strong&gt;: big, mutually-exclusive affairs that will bundle many mods together
and act as a basis for more mods.  Also sometimes called a "subgame".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we have to consider two &lt;strong&gt;games&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minetest Game&lt;/strong&gt;: the basic standard game for Minetest.  It's a
hyper-simplified version of Minecraft with no mobs or anything.   This is the
basis for most Minetest mods - most Minetest mods are only playable on
&lt;strong&gt;Minetest game&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mineclone 2&lt;/strong&gt;: a game for mineclone that makes the game stylistically and
gameplay-wise as similar to Minecraft as is feasible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minetest games and mods are typically downloaded from the Minetest &lt;a href="https://content.minetest.net/"&gt;Content
DB&lt;/a&gt;), which has a nice, easy-to-use browser built
into Minetest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the contentDB downloader is designed to be used from the offline client
- it can be executed within our online dedicated server running on the Pi4.  So
  we have to deploy the mods and games into Minetest &lt;em&gt;manually&lt;/em&gt;.  Fortunately,
  it's not as bad as all that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Mods and Games in minetest-server on Raspbian/Debian&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meat of the work we're going to be doing is in
&lt;code&gt;/var/games/minetest-server/.minetest&lt;/code&gt;.  Note that &lt;code&gt;.minetest&lt;/code&gt; is a dot-folder,
and so is hidden from &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; unless you use &lt;code&gt;ls -a&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three directories within the "minetest" directory that we care about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.minetest    
├── games
├── mods
└── worlds
    └── world
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These same three directories exist on your local copy of minetest running on
your Windows machine (or Android tablet), and will contain the same kind of
files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this means is that you can download and debug mods using the "Content DB"
system in the minetest client, and then deploy the packaged-up game or world up
to the minetest server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, to start we're going to keep it simple.  We're going to download
MineClone 2, create a world with it, and then deploy it to our server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Warning about the worlds folder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until we're setting up multiple servers and I'll go into more details, a word of
warning: The only folder in your &lt;code&gt;worlds&lt;/code&gt; folder on the Pi4 minetest-server can
be &lt;code&gt;world&lt;/code&gt;.  We'll get into more elaborate changes later.  For now - if you put
anything else in that folder, minetest-server stops working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Getting Started with MineClone 2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://forum.minetest.net/viewtopic.php?t=16407"&gt;MineClone 2 can be downloaded from the minetest
forum&lt;/a&gt; where its development
is publicly run, but &lt;a href="https://content.minetest.net/packages/Wuzzy/mineclone2/"&gt;it can also be obtained from
contentdb&lt;/a&gt;, and the
forum crashes pretty often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download it and unzip it into your &lt;code&gt;minetest\games&lt;/code&gt; folder on your Windows PC.
Or you can fetch it from minetest contentdb itself, but we're going to use the
process I used when setting up.  So, for example, if minetest is in &lt;code&gt;c:\games&lt;/code&gt;,
then you should have &lt;code&gt;c:\games\minetest\games\mineclone2&lt;/code&gt;.  Remember this is an
opensource project, which means linux, which means case-sensitive filepaths. Get
used to thinking in all-lower-case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a new world in minetest, using "Start Game" --&gt; "New"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-05-23-Minetest-mods/minetest-new-world.jpg" alt="Minetest new world
screen" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select the "MineClone 2" game, provide a seed (I recommend &lt;code&gt;6&lt;/code&gt;, because I found
it had a pleasent starting area) and a name (call it "world" - I'll explain why
later), and click "Create". This will make our new Mineclone world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we have the mod and the world running on our local copy of Minetest and we
can deploy it to our server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Deploying MineClone 2 and our new World&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Moving files onto the Pi4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We'll be using &lt;code&gt;WinSCP&lt;/code&gt; to copy the files to our server.  We can't deploy them
&lt;em&gt;direct&lt;/em&gt; to the target location because of permissions, so we'll copy them to
the "downloads" folder and then go from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;WinSCP&lt;/code&gt; and your &lt;code&gt;pi&lt;/code&gt; credentials to connect to the pi server.  Let's
create a "minetest" folder under &lt;code&gt;/home/pi/Downloads&lt;/code&gt; (aka &lt;code&gt;~/Downloads&lt;/code&gt;). Then,
move our world and the game in there using the WinSCP upload command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-05-23-Minetest-mods/winscp.jpg" alt="WinSCP" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after uploading, we should have &lt;code&gt;/home/pi/Downloads/minetest/world&lt;/code&gt; and
&lt;code&gt;/home/pi/Downloads/minetest/mineclone2&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Moving files around on the Pi4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that's the end of GUI work, time to switch to our console.  Connect a
terminal to the Pi4 server using PutTTY.  We're going to copy some files around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we have to stop our minetest server so that it doesn't complain when we
start moving things around.  &lt;code&gt;sudo systemctl stop minetest-server&lt;/code&gt;.  Our
minetest server is shut down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let's get started with the files &lt;code&gt;cd /var/games/minetest-server/.minetest/&lt;/code&gt;
and then &lt;code&gt;sudo mkdir backup&lt;/code&gt;. We're going to make a backup folder for our extra
worlds and the like. Next we have to remove the existing world so we can replace
it with our mineclone2 world.  &lt;code&gt;sudo mv ./worlds/world/ backup&lt;/code&gt; will move the
world into the backup folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, let's move in our new world and our new game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there isn't a folder called &lt;code&gt;games&lt;/code&gt; yet, &lt;code&gt;sudo mkdir games&lt;/code&gt;.  Next, we'll
bring in mineclone2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo mv /home/pi/Downloads/minetest/mineclone2 ./games/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, we'll bring in our world&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo mv /home/pi/Downloads/minetest/world ./worlds/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we've copied the files over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Permissions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we have to transfer ownership of these 2 folders to the minetest-server
user, &lt;code&gt;Debian-minetest&lt;/code&gt; of group &lt;code&gt;games&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; sudo chown Debian-minetest:games ./games/mineclone2 -R
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;-R&lt;/code&gt; means &lt;code&gt;--recursive&lt;/code&gt;.  Now the world&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; sudo chown Debian-minetest:games ./worlds/world -R
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now we're ready.   Let's restart the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Restart the World&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo systemctl start minetest-server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we're up.  On your desktop minetest, connect to the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that by default minetest stores credentials inside the world folder so we
blew away all our users... you might have to restart with fresh users again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should find your world up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, if anything's funny, check &lt;code&gt;tail /var/log/minetest/minetest.log&lt;/code&gt; for
information about your server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Mods&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mods are deployed by the same process as games, but with an extra feature - each
mod is referenced by the World.  You can see this in the Minetest gui when
configuring a world - you've a long list of mods you can toggle on and off.  In
the file-structure, enter your &lt;code&gt;worlds/worldname&lt;/code&gt; folder and open &lt;code&gt;world.mt&lt;/code&gt; in
Nano (&lt;code&gt;sudo nano world.mt&lt;/code&gt;).  Then to enable a mod that's been installed into
your &lt;code&gt;mods&lt;/code&gt; folder, add a line to the file stating &lt;code&gt;load_mod_&amp;lt;modname&amp;gt; = true&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://dev.minetest.net/Installing_Mods"&gt;More information on this process is
here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;More Worlds!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point we've covered most of the ways running a minetest server is
different from running it locally and so you're off to the races... but what if
you want to run more than one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where we go back into working with Debian/systemd.  In order to run more
worlds, we're going to run a second minetest-server instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Fixing the Minetest World Folder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, first we need to get into the weeds.  By default minetest runs the world
named &lt;code&gt;world&lt;/code&gt;, right?  That is, the world located at
&lt;code&gt;/var/games/minetest-server/.minetest/worlds/world/&lt;/code&gt;, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;WRONG&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minetest-server by default &lt;em&gt;names&lt;/em&gt; the folder "world".  But what it actually runs
is "the only world folder in &lt;code&gt;/var/games/minetest-server/.minetest/worlds/&lt;/code&gt;".
What does that mean if there's 2 folders in
&lt;code&gt;/var/games/minetest-server/.minetest/worlds/&lt;/code&gt;?  Crashy crashy.  And we're going
to put a second world in there!  So before we do that, we have to make the
implicit explicit and tell minetest where to find our &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we start, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo systemctl stop minetest-server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, we're ready to operate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nano /etc/minetest/minetest.conf
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, look for &lt;code&gt;map-dir&lt;/code&gt; and set it as follows&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;map-dir = /var/games/minetest-server/.minetest/worlds/world/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it no longer has to &lt;em&gt;guess&lt;/em&gt; where to find the world, it has an exact
location.  So we can create a 2nd world-folder and not confuse it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo systemctl start minetest-server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And check to make sure everything's hunky dory with our existing server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Creating a new Config File&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started on our 2nd world, we need to create a new config file.  We
already have &lt;code&gt;/etc/minetest/minetest.conf&lt;/code&gt;, we're going to be copying that file
into a new 2nd file for our 2nd minetest server instance.  We can name it
whatever we like, but I like to name my worlds starting with their port number.
This is going to run on port 30002, so we'll call it &lt;code&gt;2-mineclone-survival&lt;/code&gt;,
since our first world was creative.  Well, mine was.  If yours wasn't, feel free
to make your 2nd world whatever else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo cp /etc/minetest/minetest.conf /etc/minetest/2-mineclone-survival.conf
sudo nano /etc/minetest/2-mineclone-survival.conf
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will create our 2nd file and edit it.  This will work much the same as the
first time &lt;em&gt;except&lt;/em&gt; we need to give it a new world-folder since our other
world-folder is already in use, and set a port.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, look for &lt;code&gt;port&lt;/code&gt; and set it as follows&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;port = 30002
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, look for &lt;code&gt;map-dir&lt;/code&gt; and set it as follows&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;map-dir = /var/games/minetest-server/.minetest/worlds/2-mineclone-survival/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, my world is named &lt;code&gt;2-mineclone-survival&lt;/code&gt; but you do you.  Now, mineclone
doesn't need to edit this file, so we don't have to &lt;code&gt;chmod&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;chown&lt;/code&gt; it or
anything.  That file is ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Forwarding ports&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember earlier I told you that you &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to forward 30000, but I recommended
doing 30000-30010?  If you didn't take my advice, take it now.  We're setting up
a service on 30002, you need to forward that on your router.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Creating your 2nd world&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, next step is up to you.  If you want to let minetest &lt;em&gt;create&lt;/em&gt; your 2nd world
for you, it should do that based on the settings in your conf file.  I haven't
tried that.  But if you have opinions on seed and want to hand-craft it in the
minetest client, then you can go through the previous process of deploying the
world into &lt;code&gt;2-mineclone-survival&lt;/code&gt;.  Create it, move it into place, &lt;code&gt;chown&lt;/code&gt; it,
etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Registering the Server&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's a simple command to create a 2nd server-instance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo systemctl start minetest-server@2-mineclone-survival.service
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You'll notice that I've used "2-mineclone-survival" again.  That name &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt;
match the name of your conf file.  So if you named your 2nd conf file "fred"?
&lt;code&gt;minetest-server@fred.service&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;edit (2020-07-26): I missed a step, apparently.  I noticed my server wasn't
starting on restart!  So there's an extra step here - we have to &lt;em&gt;enable&lt;/em&gt; the
service, which is analogous to "autostart" on Windows.  Enable means start on
startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo systemctl enable minetest-server@2-mineclone-survival.service
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, that &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be it.  2nd world is up and running.  Go see the server
browser and you should find two worlds on your address, one on 30000 and one on
30002.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you're done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Next Time&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/05/30/mineclone2-skins/"&gt;The skinny on skins.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/05/12/minetest-pi4-recipe/</id><title type="text">Minetest Pi4 Recipe (rpi minetest-server part 2)</title><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Continuing from my &lt;a href="http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/05/05/minetest-birthday/"&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt; on my
daughter's Minetest birthday party, here's how I built my Raspberry Pi 4
minetest server that powered the party.  To be clear: this is only my second
time this century setting up a linux-based server from scratch, so I'm pretty
novice at this.  I'm handy with a terminal console but only on Windows.  The
intended reader of this article is... well, somebody like me.  Somebody new to
Linux but very comfy with Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary><published>2020-05-12T04:00:00Z</published><updated>2020-05-12T04:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/05/12/minetest-pi4-recipe/" /><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Continuing from my &lt;a href="http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/05/05/minetest-birthday/"&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt; on my
daughter's Minetest birthday party, here's how I built my Raspberry Pi 4
minetest server that powered the party.  To be clear: this is only my second
time this century setting up a linux-based server from scratch, so I'm pretty
novice at this.  I'm handy with a terminal console but only on Windows.  The
intended reader of this article is... well, somebody like me.  Somebody new to
Linux but very comfy with Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Hardware&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Pi Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.buyapi.ca/product/raspberry-pi-4-model-b-2gb/"&gt;2GB Raspberry Pi4 with official USB
power-supply&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;32GB microSD card (some name-brand one; never buy no-name SDs on Amazon,
they'll only break your heart)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;good brands: Kingston, Samsung, Patriot, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.ca/Miuzei-Raspberry-Cooling-Aluminum-Model/dp/B07WJ8KHS6"&gt;Miuzei air-cooled case kit (includes heat-sinks and
fan)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;like all off-brand stuff on Amazon, individual listings are ephemeral, so
you may have to search for a different listing. I paid $15CAD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ethernet cable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Miuzei case comes with good easy-to-follow instructions for assembly.  There
are two possible configurations of the fan, a low-power mode and a high-power
mode.  We used the low-power mode, even on an overclocked emulation box.  It's
more than enough for our minetest server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Supporting Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This stuff you'll need for the setup process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A computer capable of running PuTTY and Minetest
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've also done some of this this from Linux and Android (don't recommend
that), but I'm going to be using Windows tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spare keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spare mouse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spare monitor/TV with HDMI hookup
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note the Pi4 uses micro-HDMI, which is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; common. I bought &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.ca/Cable-Matters-Plated-Female-Adapter/dp/B00JDRHQ58"&gt;these
adapters&lt;/a&gt;
for my Pi devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wifi or ethernet accessible to the location with all the above equipment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A router you're comfy setting port-forwarding and static-IPs on.  You might
need to Google how to do that on your router.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;OS Setup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download-and-burn the image onto a MicroSD using &lt;a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/downloads/"&gt;Raspberry Pi
Imager&lt;/a&gt;, but I prefer to download the
image manually and burn it to the MicroSD using &lt;a href="https://www.balena.io/etcher/"&gt;Balena
Etcher&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have the image burned and inserted into the Pi, you'll need to get it
set up for remoting - but the first time it's going to need a mouse, keyboard,
and HDMI-connected monitor until we can setup remoting.  I plugged the setup
into a TV and mouse/keyboard. For operating system: The system is running
Raspbian Buster (Raspbian is the Linux variant, Buster is the version number).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raspbian will walk through a pretty easy wizard after startup to connect to wifi
and set a password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Remoting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step to setting up remoting is getting a static IP bound to your
raspi.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open a terminal and run the command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ifconfig
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;will list your IP addresses and MAC addresses.  The you want &lt;code&gt;eth0&lt;/code&gt; for wired,
and &lt;code&gt;wlan0&lt;/code&gt; for wireless.  The ipv4 address we're focusing on will be labeled
&lt;code&gt;inet&lt;/code&gt;, and the mac address will be labeled &lt;code&gt;ether&lt;/code&gt; - the ipv4 address will be
generally be of the form &lt;code&gt;192.168.something.something&lt;/code&gt;.  The next steps are
router-specific: write down the &lt;code&gt;ether&lt;/code&gt; MAC info from &lt;code&gt;ifconfig&lt;/code&gt; and use it to
set up static IP for your router - still local, we're still in
&lt;code&gt;192.168.something.something&lt;/code&gt;, but we need a static one that won't change every
time we reboot.  I generally set my router to start dynamic IP addresses at
&lt;code&gt;192.168.1.100&lt;/code&gt; and use numbers &lt;code&gt;192.168.1.10&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;192.168.1.99&lt;/code&gt; for any
computer I want to give a static address. This will make port forwarding easier
in the future. The only wrinkle is that the wifi and ethernet interfaces will
each have their own MAC address and IP, and you'll have to decide which you want
to static bind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important steps afterwards are to enable SSH and the VNC Server.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, in the terminal type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo raspi-config
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will launch a simple UI for editing settings.  Use in "interface options"
enable SSH and VNC.  VNC will let you remote in for a GUI and SSH will let you
remote a terminal/text-console and file-transfers in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Remoting Clients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to install some remote admin software on your PC if you don't have it
already:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RealVNC (gui remoting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PuTTY (terminal remoting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WinSCP (file transfer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All are available from &lt;a href="https://ninite.com/"&gt;ninite.com&lt;/a&gt;.  Personally I prefer
mRemoteNG to PuTTY, but it's got a less memorable name and a more elaborate UI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confirm that you can connect PuTTY and RealVNC to your new Pi server.  You'll
need to use the IP address you set up on your router and the username (pi,
generally) and password you set up earlier in the Raspbian setup wizard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Moving into headless mode&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, your pi is now ready to be remote-only.  Unhook it from the
mouse, keyboard, and monitor and put it in its final resting place, and wire it
up with just ethernet and power.  You may have to tweak your Router settings to
switch over from Wifi to wired for static IP if you're going from a wireless
connection to wired (I actually forgot this step, so all my traffic to my pi4
was going over wifi even though it was plugged in).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Using the Terminal to hook into the Debian Buster Backports software repository&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we can install the minetest server, we have a problem: Raspbian and
Debian Buster tend to have somewhat stale software.  We need a fresher version
of Minetest, so we're going to link up to the buster-backports system for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Welcome to the terminal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We're going to be doing all this in the terminal.  On your desktop, open up
PuTTY, connect to your Pi4 device using the static-IP, the pi username, and the
password.  The linux terminal isn't as scary as you think -- after all, by
default it's so locked down you can't actually do any damage without &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt;,
which is basically Linux' way of saying "this line does something scary".  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We'll be using &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/Guide_to_Unix/Commands/File_System_Utilities"&gt;The basic list of commands we'll be working with are listed
here&lt;/a&gt;.
In particular, &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;cp&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;mv&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;rm&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;chmod&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;chown&lt;/code&gt;.  Be fearless
and stupid.  We're mostly just installing software and tweaking some files.
Worst case scenario, don't be afraid to wipe the thing and start over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Hooking into Buster-Backports&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier, raspbian Buster is &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; Debian.  Debian being a large,
popular Linux software distro, has an extensive library of programs available
for it.  And Raspbian can run Debian software... but by default, it's not hooked
up to access Debian's latest software apt software repository.  For this
Raspbian Buster device, the repository we need to connect to is called "Buster
Backports", which is to say back-ports of cutting-edge software to the "stable"
Buster version of Raspbian/Debian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, first, we need to let Raspbian know it's safe to talk to the Backports repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our terminal, we run the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-key adv --keyserver keyserver.ubuntu.com --recv-keys E0B11894F66AEC98
sudo apt-key adv --keyserver keyserver.ubuntu.com --recv-keys 7638D0442B90D010
sudo apt-key adv --keyserver keyserver.ubuntu.com --recv-keys 8B48AD6246925553
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm going to be honest, I don't know what it actually does in detail, and
generally copying pasting sudo commands into your machine is a bad idea,
especially stuff involving security keys.  But in this case, its's obviously
wiring into a something provided by Ubuntu, who being one of the big daddies of
Linux right now I tend to trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you're new to linux and PuTTY: &lt;code&gt;right-click&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;shift&lt;/code&gt;+&lt;code&gt;insert&lt;/code&gt; means paste.
That'll be handy for copying commands from here to paste in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we add the &lt;code&gt;buster-backports&lt;/code&gt; repository to the registry of apt
installation sources.  This mammoth command adds the configuration to connect to
"buster-backports" into our sources list for installing software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo 'deb http://httpredir.debian.org/debian buster-backports main contrib non-free' | sudo tee -a /etc/apt/sources.list.d/debian-backports.list
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This script I can explain.  Skip this if you're experienced in the ways of
Linux.  &lt;code&gt;echo 'deb http://yadda&lt;/code&gt; just means "output the quoted text" the &lt;code&gt;|&lt;/code&gt;
means "take the output of the command on the left of the &lt;code&gt;|&lt;/code&gt; and shove it into
the command on the right.  &lt;code&gt;tee -a somefilepath&lt;/code&gt; means "open somefilepath and
append the stuff shoved into this command at the end of that file and also echo
it to the screen so we can see it".  So we're taking the quoted line and
stuffing it at the end of the file &lt;code&gt;debian-backports.list&lt;/code&gt;, which will
effectively add the buster backports repository to our sources list so we can
now install software from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we have to let the "apt" installation system know that there's the new
source available to it, so we'll do&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get update
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and finally we're ready to start installing software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Installing and Configuring minetest-server&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked heavily from &lt;a href="https://wiki.minetest.net/Setting_up_a_server/Debian"&gt;this guide on the minetest
wiki&lt;/a&gt; but found it didn't
have much context for a novice like me so I'm going to slow it down and give you
a deep dive on the linuxisms involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Minetest-server, systemd, and an intro to file permissions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We're not going to do raw minetest, but rather "minetest-server" which installs
minetest &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; sets it up into the service system in Raspbian so it runs
securely with its own user (the user &lt;code&gt;Debian-minetest&lt;/code&gt; of group &lt;code&gt;games&lt;/code&gt;).  The
only warning is that this server-daemon approach means that a lot of the support
documents about minetest are going to be confusing for you because &lt;em&gt;we never
actually run minetest&lt;/em&gt;, which is something the docs talk about a lot.  Instead,
we tell &lt;code&gt;systemd&lt;/code&gt;, Raspbian's service manager, to do that for us.  It does on
startup and handles the details. Helpful, but opaque.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Quick intro to file-permissions and Linux users&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One wrinkle about this is that our &lt;code&gt;pi&lt;/code&gt; user isn't actually involved in running
the software.  Minetest-server actually uses its own linux user - so there's a
separate account responsible for running the server, and any time it needs to
look at a file we have to grant permission or ownership to that user to muck
with that file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we're going to be needing to get acquainted with some linux commands.  We
won't be using them much until we really get into the weeds with our minetest
server, but for now you should meet them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;chown&lt;/code&gt; is "change file owner/group".  We need to use this to assign ownership
of a file or folder to our service-user, who is named &lt;code&gt;Debian-minetest&lt;/code&gt; of group
&lt;code&gt;games&lt;/code&gt;.  So to assign a file to &lt;code&gt;Debian-minetest&lt;/code&gt;, we do&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo chown Debian-minetest:games &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Optionally with a &lt;code&gt;--recursive&lt;/code&gt; flag if you want to do it to every file in a
directory-tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, to grant permissions for that user, we're going to use &lt;code&gt;chmod&lt;/code&gt;, which
is "change mode" but is really about modifying file permissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You'll notice we usually call commands with &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; parameters, but in the case of
&lt;code&gt;chmod&lt;/code&gt;, we use &lt;code&gt;+&lt;/code&gt; parameters - this is something I have not gotten used to
since it is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a thing in windows/powershell scripting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo chmod +rwx &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This grants the owner &lt;strong&gt;r&lt;/strong&gt;ead, &lt;strong&gt;w&lt;/strong&gt;rite, and e&lt;strong&gt;x&lt;/strong&gt;ecute permissions to a
file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, you can use a directory (or a wildcard like *) instead of a filename, and
you can have it do the action to everything in the directory tree by using
&lt;code&gt;--recursive&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; is how to list the contents of a directory, but we want &lt;code&gt;ls -l&lt;/code&gt; to
list them and show the owner and permissions so we can be sure we did the above
right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I'm getting pretty deep into the weeds, but file permissions were 99% of
my struggle since they're barely a thing on Windows, so I figured it was worth
breaking it down here before we go any deeper - hopefully if anything goes
sideways, you now have enough to unmangle a file permission or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Install and config&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, install minetest-server from the buster-backports source we just finished
hooking into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get -t buster-backports install minetest-server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then create and setup our config file.  That's where a lot of the meat will be
happening - we've got the game installed, but our server is private and
unsecured and all that.  We want something we can &lt;em&gt;control&lt;/em&gt;.  My daughter and
her friends are playing in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#unzip the starting config - I'm pretty sure this step is unnecessary 
#and might ruin privileges on minetest.conf .
#Only do this if /etc/minetest/minetest.conf wasn't created automatically
sudo zcat /usr/share/doc/minetest/minetest.conf.example.gz &amp;gt; /etc/minetest/minetest.conf

#open the config up in the editor to get to work
sudo nano /etc/minetest/minetest.conf
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The file &lt;code&gt;/etc/minetest/minetest.conf&lt;/code&gt; contains a pretty-well-annotated config
of everything about our minetest server.  The only big gotcha is that you &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt;
set a &lt;code&gt;bind_address&lt;/code&gt; to make your server accessible to anybody.  The default is
0.0.0.0, which is supposed to mean "accept all incoming connections" but somehow
either minetest or systemd get cranky and instead accept &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; connections.  So
take that static IP you set on your server way back at the beginning of this
recipe, and put it in &lt;code&gt;bind_address&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, you want a password, at least until you're ready to unleash this thing
on the public world.  Set &lt;code&gt;default_password&lt;/code&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can set a nice name, grant players some default privileges, and publicize it
in the server browser so players can search you out in the listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start?  Probably focus on &lt;code&gt;bind_address&lt;/code&gt;, a &lt;code&gt;server_name&lt;/code&gt;, the name of your
admin user (&lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt;) and a &lt;code&gt;default_password&lt;/code&gt;.  Maybe decide if you want your
first world to be creative mode or not&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you've never used &lt;em&gt;Nano&lt;/em&gt; before, it's actually pretty easy in a linuxy way -
normal cursor controls (don't try to mouse-scroll though), but doesn't use
windows-standard hotkeys.  Everywhere in linux, ctrl-C means "break whatever's
going on", so copy-paste is highlight and rclick instead.  Don't try to undo
with ctrl-Z either, that means suspend the current program and switch to console
(&lt;code&gt;fg %1&lt;/code&gt; to come back, meaning put suspended app &lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; back in the
&lt;strong&gt;f&lt;/strong&gt;ore&lt;strong&gt;g&lt;/strong&gt;round).  &lt;code&gt;Ctrl&lt;/code&gt; + the keys listed along the bottom are the hotkeys,
like &lt;code&gt;ctrl&lt;/code&gt;+&lt;code&gt;w&lt;/code&gt; to search, &lt;code&gt;ctrl&lt;/code&gt;+&lt;code&gt;o&lt;/code&gt; to save, &lt;code&gt;ctrl&lt;/code&gt;+&lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; to quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, our first chmod command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#enable writing of the log file for all users so we can see what’s going on
sudo chmod a+rw /var/log/minetest/minetest.log
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need Minetest to be allowed to write to the minetest log file.  The "a" in
that chmod means "all users", we're going to keep this simple.  I know you have
to do this step because I &lt;em&gt;didn't&lt;/em&gt; do it and it errored out when I tried to
start up the server... I don't know, if the file doesn't exist yet just start
the server and then chmod it afterwards. Or like &lt;code&gt;echo '' |
/var/log/minetest/minetest.log&lt;/code&gt; to create it blank.  Whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Start it up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that our Minetest server is installed and configured, it's time to cross our
fingers and start it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, meet &lt;code&gt;systemctl&lt;/code&gt;.  That's systemd's tool for you to manage services that
it runs for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo systemctl start minetest-server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means we let it rip.  For future reference, there's also &lt;code&gt;systemctl stop&lt;/code&gt;
and &lt;code&gt;systemctl restart&lt;/code&gt; that do what they sound like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install the minetest desktop program onto another machine, or even an Android
phone (or hell, vnc into the raspi and install the desktop version of minetest -
it's barely usable but enough to check connections) and try to connect to your
server by the local &lt;code&gt;192.168.something.something&lt;/code&gt; static address.  This will
confirm you've got the minetest server running.  Don't forget your
&lt;code&gt;default_password&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it doesn't work?  Check &lt;code&gt;/var/log/minetest/minetest.log&lt;/code&gt;.  You can read the
whole file with the command &lt;code&gt;cat /var/log/minetest/minetest.log&lt;/code&gt;, or just the
very end of the file with &lt;code&gt;tail /var/log/minetest/minetest.log&lt;/code&gt;.  You really
want to see the line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Server for gameid="minetest" listening on 192.168.something.something:30000.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don't see it yet, keep checking with &lt;code&gt;tail
/var/log/minetest/minetest.log&lt;/code&gt; for about a minute. If there's an error in
there, take it seriously and try to figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it does work and you connect?  Celebrate!  And while you're in there, log in
with your admin user (the one you set as &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; in the minetest.conf) and use
the gui to change their password, since you'll be giving that one away to your
friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Getting your server into the public internet.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We're going to do a bit more tweaking of the minetest.conf, so let's stop the
server for a minute with &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo systemctl stop minetest-server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;... you're getting the hang of this right?  Remember, use ctrl-R to find old
commands in the history so you're not typing that mouthful over and over again.
Also tab-completion.  Als the up and down keys to find previous commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This part's a bit awkward because I have a domain name pointing at my house, and
you might not have that.  If you do have one, then set that on &lt;code&gt;server-address&lt;/code&gt;
in your minetest.conf to point it there.  Otherwise, leave the &lt;code&gt;server-address&lt;/code&gt;
line commented out with a &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt;... I've read it &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; work but I haven't tried
it myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you're in minetest.conf, you can also set &lt;code&gt;server_announce = true&lt;/code&gt; because
your server is passworded with a secure password so you won't get random
griefers smashing it up.  You set a &lt;code&gt;default_password&lt;/code&gt;, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, the next step here is setting up port-forwarding on your router.  By
default, the minetest server runs on port 30000.  That's thirty-thousand, not
three-thousand (had to explain it to my daughter a few times).  In your router,
get all incoming UDP traffic coming to 30000 forwarded to that
192.168.something.something static IP.  Now you're on the public internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let's start it back up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo systemctl start minetest-server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system will take a minute to start up - you can tail the log to check on its
progress.  Give it a minute or two and then search of your &lt;code&gt;server-name&lt;/code&gt; in the
minetest desktop GUI server-browser.  Hopefully it's online and you can connect!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Yay, it Works!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except that it's just vanilla minetest game.  It's not Mineclone2. Also, where's
our Mumble server, you want me to type chat into the console like a caveman?
Still, at the end of this article, we've got something useful!  You and your
friends can play vanilla Minetest game on your pi4 server now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/05/23/minetest-mods/"&gt;Next time, more stuff.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/05/05/minetest-birthday/</id><title type="text">Minetest Birthday (rpi minetest-server part 1)</title><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Okay, this is part one of a multi-part... well, I guess we can't use the term
"postmortem" that's popular in software development, since it's kind of morbid
for a birthday.  We'll call it an "after-action report".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, we had to handle the challenge of "how do you run a 10th birthday
party with kids under social distancing"?  My answer was cupcakes, Zoom, a
Raspberry Pi 4, and the open-source clone of Minecraft called
&lt;a href="https://www.minetest.net"&gt;Minetest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary><published>2020-05-05T04:00:00Z</published><updated>2020-05-05T04:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/05/05/minetest-birthday/" /><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Okay, this is part one of a multi-part... well, I guess we can't use the term
"postmortem" that's popular in software development, since it's kind of morbid
for a birthday.  We'll call it an "after-action report".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, we had to handle the challenge of "how do you run a 10th birthday
party with kids under social distancing"?  My answer was cupcakes, Zoom, a
Raspberry Pi 4, and the open-source clone of Minecraft called
&lt;a href="https://www.minetest.net"&gt;Minetest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Preamble&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, my daughter is really into Minecraft, in the typical sense that saying
"really into" understates the situation.  I looked into running the party on
name-brand Minecraft, but for a variety of reasons (not all of them good) I
decided to find an alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I looked into an open-source reimplementation of Minecraft called Minetest
that I'd been studiously ignoring, created by hobbyists.  The good news was that
it looked like it would meet my needs.  The bad news was that the installation
process was a lot to ask of parents.  So, a 2-part party was planned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, a Zoom meeting to say happy-birthday and blow out the candles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For those parents who had gotten through the install-and-config process, a
Minetest sandbox for the kids to play in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The Zoom Party&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do you sing Happy Birthday and blow out candles and eat cake at a
birthday party spread across about a dozen households?  Simple, with Zoom, and
&lt;a href="http://www.westdalecupcakes.com/"&gt;Cupcakes of Westdale Village&lt;/a&gt;.  This created
a fun wrinkle that all the children got to order their own personal flavour of
cupcake (and a 2nd-choice in case there was a problem).  So, the day before the
party, we gloved up and put on our masks and delivered cupcakes and goodie bags
to all of our attendees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Cupcakes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-05-05-Minetest-birthday/cupcake.jpg" alt="Cupcake" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, we had to go back to the shop to  replace a few of the cupcakes
because my son did not understand that (a) the boxes are not sealed shut, and
(b) they have to stay right-side-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every goody-bag included a candle as well, so every child got to blow out their
own cake as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Zoom&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The zoom software actually impresses me, mostly because I've been working with a
lot of the alternatives and they're kind of awful.  A gallery full of screaming
kids, and not using proper headsets, and it works pretty well.  Doing the same
with Mumble creates a nightmarish feedback loop that will feel like being
stabbed in the ear.  Sometimes the audio seems to kick in late, and there's a
lot of latency, and it seems to have a perverse and inexplicable logic for
picking volume for the kids, but it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zoom seems to be consistently dropping the 40 minute limit for free accounts
over the weekends, which was a big help.  Honestly the biggest thing that
impresses me with zoom, at least on desktop, is that they eschew the normal
setup of accounts and logins and all that process - you download an exe for the
meeting you've been invited to and you're rolling.  No setting up a username and
password, no entering in a meeting ID.  It was the one bit of tech we didn't
have to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-05-05-Minetest-birthday/zoom_cupcakes.jpg" alt="Zoom Cupcakes" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kids were ecstatic to see each other.  It was fun for them to catch up,
although it's hard for them to manage a conversation in such a massive group.
They sang happy birthday, although the latency in Zoom makes it mathematically
impossible for anybody to keep in time so it just sounds like shouting.  A great
time was had by all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then we started up the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Planning The Minetest Party&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Pi4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's my wife's fault, really.  She bought me a Raspberry Pi 3b a year or two ago
and I've gotten the Single-Board Computer bug.  A computer that can do all sorts
of things costs less than almost any individual game I bought as a kid.  I've
since converted my old Pi 3b into a Nintendo emulator for my father-in-law, and
upgraded to a trio of Pi 4 devices for various purposes.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of these Pi 4s lives under my chest of drawers in my bedroom alongside the
wifi access-point and the Phillips Hue box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-05-05-Minetest-birthday/pi4.jpg" alt="The Pi 4" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I imagine a really weird version of Toy Story under there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the curious:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2GB Raspberry Pi4 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;32GB microSD card (some name-brand one - never buy no-name SDs on Amazon,
they'll only break your heart)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Official USB power-supply&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miuzei air-cooled case kit (includes heat-sinks and fan)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The case was fun, despite being a no-name Chinese one.  We made two of these.
My son has always fantasized about building a gaming PC so this got him screwing
parts together and taping on the heat-sinks onto the Pi4 devices.  The Miuzei
only cost a two bucks more than the "official" Pi4 case and it looks better and
has a nice silent fan to cool it for overclocking (I don't overclock this one
but the other one I made for my brother is overclocked).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My son named it Kosmos.  It runs our Minetest world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Setting Up Minetest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.minetest.net"&gt;Minetest&lt;/a&gt; is a free, open-source copy of Minecraft
made by hobbyists.  For fans of Minecraft: yeah, it's a pale shadow of the
original. The problem is that Minecraft has a proliferation of versions.  Tablet
versions, two different PC versions, and two different incompatible server
versions for running worlds. All sold separately.  I didn't want to have to
figure out which version which kids had and figure out what to do there... And
worse, the newer "bedrock" version is only really practically hosted in The
Cloud.  It doesn't let me run the world on my own hardware, and I insist on
ruling my children's game-worlds like an iron-fisted despot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I gave the hobby-made imitation a try... and found that after installing a
"subgame" called &lt;a href="https://forum.minetest.net/viewtopic.php?t=16407"&gt;MineClone 2&lt;/a&gt;
that makes it a more complete imitation of MineCraft (the stock Minetest subgame
doesn't include animals and monsters), it was a good fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For hardcore minecraft fans: Mineclone 2 is a pale imitation.  The graphics are
a bit uglier, it's a bit slower, the monsters are dumber, animals keep walking
into the river and floating away, there are gaps in the gameplay, and there's no
villages.  But for people who just want to build houses and have a stable of
rabbits, it's more than good enough.  Especially in just "Creative mode" which
turns the game into more interactive lego than an actual game with objectives
and challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-05-05-Minetest-birthday/screenshot_20200503_142525.jpg" alt="Minetest Group Screenshot" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenge with minetest is the installation process: it doesn't have
one.  The game is packed up as a raw zip file and you unzip it on your machine.
You have to suss out that the executable lives in the "bin" folder (which makes
perfect sense to nobody but us programmers), and when you run the exe you'll
have to agree to numerous Windows warnings about this unsigned, unverified
program that has been unceremoniously dumped into a folder on your computer and
is asking for network privileges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Mineclone 2 also lacks an installation process, but in a good
way: you just connect to my Minetest world and you'll automatically download
Mineclone 2.  Along with the 90 or so skins I've installed into it for the kids
to choose from.  And any other mods the server is running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-05-05-Minetest-birthday/birthday-banner.jpg" alt="Birthday Banner" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mineclone 2/Minetest also has an in-game skin-picker and lets you choose your
name.  This seems like a small thing but I've seen too many games of Minecraft
where somebody is borrowing their brother's account or something and nobody
knows who they are because it shows the wrong name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Setting Up Mumble&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another server running on my little Pi4 is &lt;a href="https://www.mumble.info/"&gt;Mumble&lt;/a&gt;.  Mumble is a wonderful
open-source voicechat system designed for gaming.  It's fast, low-resource,
low-latency and has a wonderful configuration wizard where it talks you through
getting your computer's microphone configured just right to make sure all your
friends will have the best experience talking to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone &lt;strong&gt;hated&lt;/strong&gt; it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The config wizard is difficult, it has a bizarre cryptographic-key-based
authentication system, and we were unable to get it working on our friends' mac.
Most unforgivably it has no echo-cancelling to speak of so when our friends
joined in a dry-run using their straight laptop speaker and microphone instead
of a proper headset, the feedback-loop was ear-splitting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'll still insist it's the right tool for enthusiasts - the sound is crystal
clear and there's none of the delay that causes awkward interrupting and
cross-talk in Zoom.  But not for a birthday party, unless it's a birthday party
full of programmers and gamers where everybody has a good headset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we realized that Mumble was a usability disaster, we changed the plan to
just use Zoom for the minetest game too.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a four-page document for parents about the software we were using for
this party, URLs, passwords, etc.  Three of them were on Mumble.  I should've
realized it when I had to add the section about "configuring push-to-talk" but
I'm stubborn. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We kept the Mumble server as "plan B" if Zoom didn't work well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The Minetest Party&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not everybody could join.  I assume some parents saw the PDF I sent and noped
the heck out of doing tech-support for a 10 year old on a Sunday afternoon and I
don't blame them one bit.  But a good crowd of kids joined the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-05-05-Minetest-birthday/g-gaming.jpg" alt="Daughter Playing" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a hit.  I had to furiously type teleport commands as fast as I could to
get the kids all into the same area to introduce them and give them the lay of
the land:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Explain how to play and the differences between Minetest and Minecraft.
Everybody had it down inside of 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The world is backed up and we're reverting it after the party so anything you
make is going bye-bye.  This was mostly to prevent any tantrums if my
daughters' meticulously-constructed villages got obliterated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to pick skins.  This was, of course, their first question.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, apparently you can't teleport somebody out of a minecart in minetest.
This was a problem when people would not know how to dismount (look down and
rclick) and my main tool for rescuing trapped and lost kids was teleporting
them.  I had to enlist my son to be assistant-teleporter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, I had to juggle this and try to debug issues with people who
couldn't make it through the installation and game-joining process.  That was
hard - trying to isolate and work with one frustrated parent in a noisy Zoom
room is excruciating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-05-05-Minetest-birthday/double-screenshot.jpg" alt="Full Screenshot" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;note: faces of my daughters' friends redacted.  Also, this is my son's
screenshot, I was answering those support requests in chat on whisper from
another machine.  And yes, my desktop is messy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zoom got the job done for audio, barely.  My kids are &lt;em&gt;loud&lt;/em&gt;.  I would see my
daughter grabbing the mic of her headset and practically jamming it into her
mouth to holler to her friends to come follow her and explore the underground
minecart tracks.  I kept having to explain to them that they don't have to
shout, their friends' ears are &lt;em&gt;two inches from their mouths&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed a Tylenol and fresh air after 20 minutes of that.  The kids went on for
2 hours, and I have no idea how they did it.  One challenge I didn't expect was
that, because this was a completely open sandbox - no challenge or objective -
the kids tended to follow just schoolyard rules of making up activities.  This
creates the usual problem with all the kids clamoring for each others'
attention, compounded by the fact that they're doing that all directly in my
ears.  I figure a more traditional online gaming format like a deathmatch
would've solved that non-objective problem but created a whole slew of new ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the final act they had fun destroying my daughters' meticulously constructed
village with a rain of killer bunnies, lava, and explosive minecarts (see the
previous note about taking a backup of my daughters' world before we started).
I had to wipe the objects from the world multiple times because mineclone's
animals are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; coded to support large-scale use and the world would crawl
when they created too many of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2020-05-05-Minetest-birthday/lava-and-bunnies.jpg" alt="Lava and Killer Bunnies" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah, overall?  Definitely a success.  My daughter and her friends are
talking about meeting up regularly in our little mineclone world.  Meanwhile I'm
trying to figure out what game to try next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Next Time&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next post, &lt;a href="http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/05/12/minetest-pi4-recipe/"&gt;I'll get into the weeds of the setup process and gotchas for getting
these servers set up on a Pi4.  Recipes!  Linux!  Sudo all the things!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/04/08/ip-webcam/</id><title type="text">Using your phone as a Webcam on Windows and Android</title><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What with covid-19, a lot of people are remoting and not a lot of people have
webcams. But everybody's got a smartphone. So here's a guide on how to use your
smartphone as a webcam with Android an Windows over wifi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is pretty adminny. If you're not comfy with that you might need to look at
other approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One important wrinkle is performance: It runs down the battery on my phone, and
it slams the CPU on my desktop with interrupts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note that none of the software I'm recommending in this guide is open-source.
I cannot guarantee that the software discussed below has no malicious secret
intent.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</summary><published>2020-04-08T04:00:00Z</published><updated>2020-04-08T04:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.pxtl.ca/2020/04/08/ip-webcam/" /><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What with covid-19, a lot of people are remoting and not a lot of people have
webcams. But everybody's got a smartphone. So here's a guide on how to use your
smartphone as a webcam with Android an Windows over wifi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is pretty adminny. If you're not comfy with that you might need to look at
other approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One important wrinkle is performance: It runs down the battery on my phone, and
it slams the CPU on my desktop with interrupts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note that none of the software I'm recommending in this guide is open-source.
I cannot guarantee that the software discussed below has no malicious secret
intent.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I get into the details: if you don't like my guide there is also &lt;a href="http://ip-webcam.appspot.com/static/doc.html"&gt;the
official guide&lt;/a&gt; from the developer
of the tools I'm describing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Setting up your phone as a server&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you need to get your Android phone onto a static IP. So go to Settings -&gt;
About -&gt; Status to find your Wi-fi MAC address, and in your router's DHCP/LAN
settings, you need to bind that address to a fixed IP. Also take note of &lt;em&gt;which&lt;/em&gt;
wifi network your phone lives on, if you have more than one in your home or
workplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, you need to install &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pas.webcam&amp;amp;hl=en_CA"&gt;IP
Webcam&lt;/a&gt;
on your android phone. This turns your phone into a video server - which is why
it needs a static IP. Run IP Webcam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Recommended settings:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IP WEBCAM SETTINGS -&gt; Video Preferences
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set the "main" camera to the front-facing camera. I know the rear-camera is
better but this is just easier to set up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set the "Video Resolution" to 640x480 or lower. I found performance problems
at higher resolution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CONNECTION SETTINGS -&gt; Local Broadcasting
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a Login and Password.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm assuming your network is secure so we're not going to fuss with SSL, I
couldn't make SSL work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just to be safe, don't get naked in front of your phone while it's running
the server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Notes on "run in background":&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IP WebCam has the option to run in background, but I found the notification icon
that indicates this is happening easy-to-miss and so it would be very easy to
accidentally leave it broadcasting your life. It does save power because you can
shut down the video view and do other things while it's streaming, but I
recommend not using it. If power is a problem, get a power-cable for your
computer desk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Starting it up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that your settings are confirmed, click "start server". It will show the
live video from your phoen that it is broadcasting, along with the address if
the webserver your phone is running - eg http://192.168.1.X:8080. Note that this
is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the address of the raw stream, but of a website you can use to
configure your device. Feel free to hit that address with your browser to try
it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual video feed lives at http://192.168.1.X:8080/video. Note the /video
directory. It's over HTTP, so again you can hit it with your browser. You'll be
prompted for username and password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leave the server running while we set up the client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Setting up your Windows PC as a client&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, confirm that your Windows PC is on the same WiFi network as your phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we install the client software. We're using &lt;a href="https://ip-webcam.appspot.com/"&gt;IP Camera
Adapter&lt;/a&gt; which will allow you to connect your
Windows PC to the HTTP videostream and use it as a webcam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install the software. When completed, open the app "Configure IP Camera Adapter"
that is now present in your start menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Type in the camera feed URL - remember this is the one that ends in "/video".
So in total it should be something like http://192.168.1.X:8080/video . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Key in your username and password.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click "Autodetect" - this will test our connection to your phone and read in
its resolution. It should match whatever you set back in the server setup
step.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;OK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now use your video-chat program of choice's "video test" tool to confirm it
works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did it work? Yay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No? You're on your own, bud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find it best to keep my video stream &lt;em&gt;off&lt;/em&gt; and just keep the button to turn my
phone into a camera on my phone's home-screen. You will see a wierd backwards
text in your video-feed if your computer cannot reach the phone. So when a
videochat starts, I open the app, scroll to the bottom and click "start", and
then put my phone in place to work as a camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that the camera mode does run down the battery, so it may be handy to
have a charge-cable near whatever cradle-like setup you've rigged for your phone
at your desk.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://www.pxtl.ca/2017/03/11/xoutput/</id><title type="text">XOutput v0.2.0</title><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/Pxtl/XOutput/releases/tag/v0.2.0"&gt;I've released my first version of my fork of XOutput.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It's a simple wrapper that allows you to rebind a DInput gamepad as an XInput gamepad.&lt;br /&gt;
Since most games are standardized on XInput (XBox360 controllers), 
this allows you to make an existing gamepad masquerade as an XBox360 controller. &lt;/p&gt;
</summary><published>2017-03-11T05:00:00Z</published><updated>2017-03-11T05:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.pxtl.ca/2017/03/11/xoutput/" /><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/Pxtl/XOutput/releases/tag/v0.2.0"&gt;I've released my first version of my fork of XOutput.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It's a simple wrapper that allows you to rebind a DInput gamepad as an XInput gamepad.&lt;br /&gt;
Since most games are standardized on XInput (XBox360 controllers), 
this allows you to make an existing gamepad masquerade as an XBox360 controller. &lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>