<rss xmlns:a10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Pxtl.ca</title><link>http://www.pxtl.ca/rss.xml</link><description>Pxtl.ca</description><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pxtl.ca/2023/10/24/dryer-repair/</guid><link>http://www.pxtl.ca/2023/10/24/dryer-repair/</link><author>pxtl@hotmail.com</author><category>Blog</category><title>Kenmore Dryer Repair</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Once again, everything is made of garbage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-10-24-dryer-repair/failed-coil.jpg" alt="failed heating coil in dryer" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 04:00:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2023-10-24T04:00:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Once again, everything is made of garbage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-10-24-dryer-repair/failed-coil.jpg" alt="failed heating coil in dryer" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our dryer failed.  I feel like I have a moral responsibility to attempt to
repair anything before making it waste. So I’m trying my hand at the dryer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disassembly was harder than it needed to be.  I kept thinking it would be like a
'90s computer where you do the screws and then it opens, but it turns out the
dryer is the opposite - while everything internal is mounted with screws, the
case is opened with pry-bars and brute force.  So I undid all the screws at the
back, realized I'd unmounted some kind of plate, and then carefully lined it
back up reaching through and screwed it back together.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched a bunch of videos about how to pull the thing apart and check it -
found a working voltmeter and tested all 3 thermal switches that I found.  The
only real problem was testing the coil - the plate where the coil was mounted
had a nice open hole where the coil's port should have been, but instead the
coil's port was far out of reach.  I assume it's a safety thing - there's 3000+
watts coursing through that port, I assume they didn't want it easily touched
when you can pry the lid off with a blade screwdriver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So then I gave in and pulled it apart properly.  It's especially difficult since
the last HVAC guys who did our house moved the furnace closer to the dryer and
so it's miserably cramped, it was very hard to get the drum out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly I didn't realize that the whole tub joint pops upwards so I detached the
tub from the join and then found the join comes off pretty easy anyways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-10-24-dryer-repair/failed-coil-context.jpg" alt="failed coil in context of disassembled dryer" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically, the "some kind of plate" that I'd painstakingly removed and
re-added?  That was the thing the coil was mounted on, so I had to remove it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, the broken coil was plainly visible, so I ordered in new parts.  I also
&lt;a href="https://lemmy.ca/post/7887807"&gt;asked on Lemmy&lt;/a&gt; if there were any thoughts about
what to do while I was in there and got the advice to replace the belt and
re-lube the ball-axle while the drum was out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the dryer has been disassembled and vacuumed, the dead coil removed, the
new coil swapped in, ready to reassemble as soon as the new belt arrives. I was
surprised how much of the brown schmutz in the heater was just ash from the coils
- it dusted off quite shiny after I replaced the coil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-10-24-dryer-repair/clean-coil.jpg" alt="clean and repaired coil plate" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a little worried about the visibly duller part of the heater assembly,
hopefully that won’t absorb too much heat - I tried to cluster the coils a bit
looser there to compensate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s even visible on the reverse side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-10-24-dryer-repair/burn-through.jpg" alt="burn-through mark" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, I’m reassembling tomorrow when the new belt arrives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the belt arrived and I went to Rona and picked up some (too expensive)
axle grease and aluminum tape.  The tape was to repair the exhaust hose and to
replace the disintegrated rubber strap that was sealing the internal exhaust
tube on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-10-24-dryer-repair/taped-internal-exhaust.jpg" alt="taped internal exhaust detail" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, also the wiring diagram tore when I pulled it out, so I photocopied
that and figured I should keep it and... well, when all you have is a hammer,
everything looks like a nail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-10-24-dryer-repair/taped-wiring-copy.jpg" alt="taped wiring diagram copy" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then we got into reassembling it.  Brought in a helper and we re-lubed the
axle, put everything back in place, and screwed it all back together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-10-24-dryer-repair/reassembly-helper.jpg" alt="reassembly with helper" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only one screw went missing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-10-24-dryer-repair/reassembled.jpg" alt="reassembled dryer" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had my kid sit with it for a full cycle armed with the fire extinguisher (just
in case) while I went and picked up my other kid (late) from climbing gym.  It
all worked!&lt;/p&gt;
</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pxtl.ca/2023/10/03/a-tale-of-two-pharmacies/</guid><link>http://www.pxtl.ca/2023/10/03/a-tale-of-two-pharmacies/</link><author>pxtl@hotmail.com</author><category>Blog</category><title>A Tale of Two Pharmacies</title><description>&lt;p&gt;What follows is the story of why I no longer go to my old pharmacy.  This is
recounted from memory, and some of the details may be inaccurate, but the gist
is there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;drops in at local pharmacy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I'm running out of my meds, can you refill them?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Sorry, you have to come closer to refill-day, so come back Saturday."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Okay, I'll come back then."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Okay,  it's Saturday, here to refill my meds."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"... yeah, you're out of refills.  We'll have to talk to your doctor."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"... but it's the weekend?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Oh, we'll sort it out on Monday."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;

</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 04:00:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2023-10-03T04:00:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What follows is the story of why I no longer go to my old pharmacy.  This is
recounted from memory, and some of the details may be inaccurate, but the gist
is there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;drops in at local pharmacy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I'm running out of my meds, can you refill them?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Sorry, you have to come closer to refill-day, so come back Saturday."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Okay, I'll come back then."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Okay,  it's Saturday, here to refill my meds."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"... yeah, you're out of refills.  We'll have to talk to your doctor."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"... but it's the weekend?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Oh, we'll sort it out on Monday."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Okay, it's Monday, can you get in touch with my doc?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Sure!  We'll fax that.  Come back tomorrow and we'll have it sorted out."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"No, I'm on my last pill, it has to be refilled today."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"You know you're supposed to give us 48 hours notice, right?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ಠ_ಠ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Yes, I know.  I tried."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Okay, we'll fax them now.  Come back this evening."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Okay."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;calls towards the end of the work day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Hi, are my meds in yet?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"What?  We don't have any meds for you on file."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"No, my doctor faxed something?" &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"No they didn't."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;calls doctor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We definitely faxed them.  We'll fax them again."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;phones pharmacy back&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Hi, are my meds in yet?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"What?  We don't have any meds for you on file."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Can you check if you got faxed anything about my meds?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Oh, yes, we see that now, we got a fax.  Can you come in Wednesday to pick them
up?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"No, I'm on my last pill."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sigh on phone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"You know you're supposed to give us 48 hours notice, right?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I tried."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Okay, we'll get that ready for you, please hold."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Sorry, we're all out of those.  They've been all out for a while.  It's on
back-order, everybody's out."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;stifles why-am-I-just-hearing-about-this-now-screaming-rage&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Uh, what do I do?  I'm on my last pill."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Okay, we've got a one week supply to give you.  Can you come tomorrow?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I can come now."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"But we're closing in 15 minutes."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I'm out walking the dog. I'm literally at your door."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;".... Okay."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;gets my one week supply&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Thanks.  What do I do for next week?  Will there be more then?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Oh no, it's &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; out-of-stock.  But the half-dose pills aren't.  We've got
those, so you can just double-them.  Call your doc and we'll get that sorted."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Great."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;frustrated and needing to get back to my life, I give it a few days.  Bad
mistake.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;calling dr office&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Hi, they're out of my meds everywhere, can I get prescribed the halfsies
instead?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Uh, your doctor has been prescribing those to a lot of people and nobody's
complained yet."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Well the pharmacy disagrees."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The pharmacy is allowed to give you the halfsies sans scrip if they're out of
the regular dose."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I did not know that. Do they know that?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Whatever. They obviously don't want to without a scrip.  Doc will be in
tomorrow, we'll sort it out."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Calls pharmacy next day afternoon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"So d'you have my meds?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"What?  We don't have any meds for you on file."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"No, I mean my doctor said they'd fax today."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Yeah, they didn't. For what?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The halfsies.  They also said you can do the substitution yourself when you're
out-of-stock on something."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Yeah, we can't do that, they're wrong."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Fine. Okay, I'll call my doctor again about sending the fax."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;calls doctor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Did you send them that fax?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We sent them the fax again.  We'll send it again again."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Great, thanks."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;at this point life intervenes, and I still have one pill for tomorrow morning -
so wait until next day to call&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Hi, do you have my halfsies?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We can have them for you day after tomorrow."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Day after tomorrow!? ... Sorry for raising my voice but I'm on my last pill,
what happened?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Well, they're not in stock."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"What."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"But you can get them from other pharmacies."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I was told they were in stock here."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"They're not."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Fine.  I'll call around."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;thinks angrily about the last time this happened and scrip was lost in limbo
between two pharmacies and had to get re-prescribed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Calls Other Pharmacy. On hold for 15 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Hi, do you have these meds?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"What? No, nobody has them."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I mean the halfsies."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Oh!  Let me check."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;on hold even longer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Yep, we've got them. We'll call your pharmacy and get the scrip transferred."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Great!"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;gives this an hour to work out, calls my pharmacy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Hi!  Are my drugs transferred to Other Pharmacy?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We're just putting the scrip on hold and doing the paperwork, we'll get it sent
to them in five, then call them."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Great! I'll give them 20."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;15 minutes later, call Other Pharmacy anticipating being stuck on hold for a
long time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;phone picks up quickly!  Yay!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Hi!  Have they transferred my scrip?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Let me check."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Nope, they haven't.  I'll give them a call right away.  Can you call back in
half an hour?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Okay."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(；￣д￣)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;calls Other Pharmacy half hour later&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;On hold.  Every few minutes get redirected back to main menu.  Go back on hold&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;run out of minutes on phone (I'm cheap, okay?), buy more minutes.  Call again.
Go back on holdm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Give up, drive out to Other Pharmacy, arrive and find pharmacist juggling phone
in one hand and serving a mob of customers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Uh..."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Yeah, they still haven't faxed me yet, I'll call them now."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Okay."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;more waiting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Any luck?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"They said they'd fax again."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;more waiting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;even more waiting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Uh, are my meds-"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I'll call them again."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;even more waiting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;aimlessly wander the tiny drugstore playing on my phone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Martin?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;perk up&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Yes?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"They were faxing your prescription to the wrong number. They didn't figure it
out until they got a confused call from Alberta. Gimme a minute to do the
paperwork and we'll have you on your way."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that's how I got my meds.&lt;/p&gt;
</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pxtl.ca/2023/09/24/overwatch2-4v4/</guid><link>http://www.pxtl.ca/2023/09/24/overwatch2-4v4/</link><author>pxtl@hotmail.com</author><category>Games</category><title>How I would've designed Overwatch 2</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Okay I’ve been playing the Overwatch 2 anniversary events and considering how
many of them are small-group team-vs-team things (Catch the Patchmari,
Starwatch). I slept on these the first time through and playing them now I’m
surprised at how much I’m enjoying them, particularly StarWatch despite some of
its dumber ideas (like the AI-controlled Doomfist). This has cemented my
previous opinion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OW2 should’ve been 4v4 (2 DPS, 1 tank, 1 healer) with some kind of
fast-respawning mechanic for the healer, and a standard double-team mode (8v8)
either in quickplay or the arcade or something&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the number of heroes and the popularity of the roles reflects the number in
play - there are twice as many DPS heroes to choose from, twice as many DPS
players, and twice as many on the team.&lt;/p&gt;

</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 04:00:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2023-09-24T04:00:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Okay I’ve been playing the Overwatch 2 anniversary events and considering how
many of them are small-group team-vs-team things (Catch the Patchmari,
Starwatch). I slept on these the first time through and playing them now I’m
surprised at how much I’m enjoying them, particularly StarWatch despite some of
its dumber ideas (like the AI-controlled Doomfist). This has cemented my
previous opinion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OW2 should’ve been 4v4 (2 DPS, 1 tank, 1 healer) with some kind of
fast-respawning mechanic for the healer, and a standard double-team mode (8v8)
either in quickplay or the arcade or something&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the number of heroes and the popularity of the roles reflects the number in
play - there are twice as many DPS heroes to choose from, twice as many DPS
players, and twice as many on the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously they would’ve needed to rework some of the healers to be able to
solo-carry the healing, and probably add more Soldier/Sombra-style off-healing
abilities for DPS characters (eg: give Reaper a way to share his vampirism), but
still: While the 5v5 gameplay is generally unpopular, a lot of competitive
players celebrate how every play feels much more impactful at those smaller
counts. In 4v4 or 3v3 games like StarWatch or Elimination, it’s even moreso -
solo-healing is intense, but at the same time in StarWatch when the healer goes
down it’s not as huge of a loss as losing both healers in regular games because
of the respawn-in-place mechanic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anybody who played Team Fortress 2 knows the huge distinction between intense,
competitive small-team 6v6 matches and the low-stress farting-around feel of the
huge 12v12 lolgames in pubs that were vastly more popular, because the diffuse
responsibility meant you weren’t letting down your whole team if you were
breaking in a new character or a new strategy. Transferring that to OW2, it
would only make sense to break away from the forced “every game must have the
same playercount” thing and embrace offering 8v8 modes for more casual play, and
4v4 modes for more competitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my mind, this was the missed opportunity of the composition rejiggering of
OW2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally, I think OW copied some things from TF2 without understanding how
they interact with lower player-counts. They copied TF2’s long rollouts and
respawn timers, but didn’t realize that this makes death way too costly in a
small-team game. In 5v5 at a good level, a single kill can basically end the
team-fight. If they want to drop player-count, they need to find a way to fix
that. Imho that’s why so many of their “Arcade” modes play with alternate
respawning mechanics, like freeze-tag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also they wanted big flashy ults without thinking how that interacts with the
rest of the game. There’s a reason that most competitive twitch-FPS games don’t
have nukes on the serious maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it were up to me?  Nerf the ults in general. Either slower build or just
lower-power. Although if you go slower-build, you need to come up with a sane
way to have the charge carry between rounds, which would be tricky to get right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also they should make No Limits and Mystery Heroes 6v6 for old time’s sake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, on the subject of the story-mode: they keep trying to make PvE happen,
when fundamentally Overwatch is designed as a PvP game.  Imho, the correct
approach is to embrace that - accept the ludonarrative disconnect and make PvP
missions that tell the story.  Regularly release a short film and a companion
PvP mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did the wrong team win for the story?  Who cares.  Does nobody want to play a
character who's critical to the story?  Have them appear for a quick scripted
scene at the beginning and end.&lt;/p&gt;
</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pxtl.ca/2023/09/19/fzero99/</guid><link>http://www.pxtl.ca/2023/09/19/fzero99/</link><author>pxtl@hotmail.com</author><category>Games</category><title>F-Zero 99</title><description>&lt;p&gt;i got a little carried away with this nostalgia game.  I loved the old F-Zero and this remake lets you play the classic against 98 other players at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LPtVwbNEmvE?si=zVh2fj70O3vx2cBs" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 04:00:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2023-09-19T04:00:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;i got a little carried away with this nostalgia game.  I loved the old F-Zero and this remake lets you play the classic against 98 other players at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LPtVwbNEmvE?si=zVh2fj70O3vx2cBs" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the game is fun but too repetitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is excellent in some ways - the old Mode7 graphics look goddamned
beautiful on a big modern HD screen, and they’ve done a brilliant job adapting
the classic assets into new ways, like the new spin-attack. The game has a
simple and clean design that adds only a little to the classic game - it handles
like the original (which is similar to MarioKart without weapons), but now boost
burns health and collisions drop coins that you can use to “superboost” which is
a short-term access to an elevated faster track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels very random, but in a fun way - like, if Fall Guys was too chaotic for
you don’t pick this up. Getting into top ranks in a race seems to depend on a
lucky melee kill (which gets you enough health to abuse the booster), or
pummeling a fortunately-placed Gold Bumper or two (which quickly give you enough
coins for the superboost). Both of those are available on a pretty random basis.
The occasional lag-spike adds even more to the randomness of play. But still,
I’m enjoying it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big flaw imho is lack of variety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so sick of Mute City and Big Blue, after only a few days playing. The main
game currently only has a 4 track rotation with 2 voting options, and voters
always take the easier option. It’s a problem that the original SNES F-Zero only
had 15 tracks, and they’re trying to keep it to Knight (Easy) League for now
except for the “expert tracks” mode which is just Port Town 2 and White Land 1.
They’re obviously going to bring in the other leagues over time, but that’s
still only 15 tracks and some of those are hard-mode-remakes of older ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also only 4 cars to choose from - there’s the speedy one, the brawler
(important in these crowded courses), the fast-recharger (remember that health
is boost) and the all-arounder. So good options to match your playstyle, but
still: only 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;F-Zero was a SNES launch-title that smashed it out of the park with music and
gameplay and graphics and style, but it was obviously made under a deadline and
so it doesn’t have an amazing amount of content, and you really feel that
playing F-Zero 99.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s just too repetitive. I loved the OG, but I’d sacrifice nostalgia for some
new, unfamiliar courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But yeah, if you’ve got access to Nintendo Switch Online, I’d definitely give it
a try. You can’t beat the price: Free is my favourite flavour. It’s easy to pick
up, the tutorial is pretty quick, and it’s fun. And it’s a Nintendo “99”
nostalgia game, which means it’s certainly going to be time-limited. Play it
while you can.&lt;/p&gt;
</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pxtl.ca/2023/09/12/more-rigid/</guid><link>http://www.pxtl.ca/2023/09/12/more-rigid/</link><author>pxtl@hotmail.com</author><category>Blog</category><title>More rigid</title><description>&lt;p&gt;If you watch "Well There's Your Problem" podcast (about engineering disasters),
Alice has an iconoclastic opinion on things like expansion plates and swivel
joints and the general flexibility of good engineering: "No, make it more
rigid!" I have taken that to heart with some recent home improvement projects.&lt;/p&gt;

</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 04:00:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2023-09-12T04:00:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you watch "Well There's Your Problem" podcast (about engineering disasters),
Alice has an iconoclastic opinion on things like expansion plates and swivel
joints and the general flexibility of good engineering: "No, make it more
rigid!" I have taken that to heart with some recent home improvement projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-09-12-more-rigid/fencepost.jpg" alt="fencepost" /&gt;
&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-09-12-more-rigid/swing-chair-binding.jpg" alt="swing-chair-binding" /&gt;
&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-09-12-more-rigid/swing-chair.jpg" alt="swing-chair" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pxtl.ca/2023/08/31/sick-pupper/</guid><link>http://www.pxtl.ca/2023/08/31/sick-pupper/</link><author>pxtl@hotmail.com</author><category>Blog</category><title>Sick Pupper</title><description>&lt;p&gt;So my dog made a mess in his crate overnight.  Not a big deal, he eats anything
he can get his mouth on, upset tummies are expected.  I've parented 3 human
babies, messes happen, I know the drill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Waffles, there's no good place in the house to wash him, so normally I take
him out to the driveway and hold him by the collar and clean him off with the
hose.  He doesn't love the cold hose-water, but I've seen him frolick in deep
puddles in January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this time I had something new to help!  I fenced in my backyard.  But on the
other hand, the back yard is all grass.  And mud.  And last time I was barefoot,
this time I was wearing flipflops.&lt;/p&gt;

</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 04:00:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2023-08-31T04:00:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So my dog made a mess in his crate overnight.  Not a big deal, he eats anything
he can get his mouth on, upset tummies are expected.  I've parented 3 human
babies, messes happen, I know the drill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Waffles, there's no good place in the house to wash him, so normally I take
him out to the driveway and hold him by the collar and clean him off with the
hose.  He doesn't love the cold hose-water, but I've seen him frolick in deep
puddles in January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this time I had something new to help!  I fenced in my backyard.  But on the
other hand, the back yard is all grass.  And mud.  And last time I was barefoot,
this time I was wearing flipflops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a strategic mistake.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not underestimate the traction of a panicky Golden in his element.  He ran
&lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt; and I skated along my now-muddy lawn in my flipflops, dragged by my
fingers hooked under his collar.  He stopped just in time to bash me against the
shed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have newfound respect for rodeo guys that hogtie livestock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm black and blue but the most bruised part of me is my ego for getting
beaten-up by a two-foot-tall 70 lb eunuch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;my poor sick pupper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-08-31-poor-sick-pupper.jpg" alt="my poor sick pupper" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pxtl.ca/2023/06/03/covid-cocktails-8/</guid><link>http://www.pxtl.ca/2023/06/03/covid-cocktails-8/</link><author>pxtl@hotmail.com</author><category>Cocktails</category><title>Covid Cocktails 8</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a heavily delayed in blogging, back in August 2021 I did my 8th round of cocktails, and hit my big goal: 100 different cocktails in a year.  I had to fly out soon, so this was a hyper-compressed rush of cocktails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Covid cocktails 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-06-03-Covid-cocktails-8/Covid-cocktails-8-collage-1024.jpg" alt="Covid cocktails 8 collage" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 04:00:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2023-06-03T04:00:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a heavily delayed in blogging, back in August 2021 I did my 8th round of cocktails, and hit my big goal: 100 different cocktails in a year.  I had to fly out soon, so this was a hyper-compressed rush of cocktails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Covid cocktails 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-06-03-Covid-cocktails-8/Covid-cocktails-8-collage-1024.jpg" alt="Covid cocktails 8 collage" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Covid Cocktails Final Bout&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New ingredient! St Germain elderflower liqueur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the &lt;strong&gt;Comte de Sureau&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5oz gin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz St Germain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.25 oz Campari&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mix with ice, pour to a rocks glass with big ice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-06-03-Covid-cocktails-8/comte-de-Sureau.jpg" alt="Comte de Sureau" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked it. The St Germain brings some sweetness and a nice floral note... but the the Collective Arts gin has such a floral flavor already I feel like it got lost a bit. I like Campari, but its effect here is subtle. In the end it mostly tasted like a sweetened and lengthened floral gin with a bitter undertone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's nice. Not really exciting, but nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm looking forward to playing more with it the St Germain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More St Germain! This time we make a &lt;strong&gt;Courtside&lt;/strong&gt; - a nice long summer drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a shaker, muddle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 hulled strawberry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 raspberries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;add&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 oz vodka&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 oz apple juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5 oz elderflower liqueur&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5 oz lime juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.33 oz sugar syrup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shake with ice, then double-strain to a Collins glass full of ice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, top with club soda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Garnish with berries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-06-03-Covid-cocktails-8/courtside.jpg" alt="Courtside" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is so incredibly easy to drink. It's a tangy berry soda. I've got to work things out with the shaker or my huge Collins glasses though - I had it with a straw so I had the strongest sip first, but after it was too dilute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, double-straining berry sludge &lt;em&gt;sucks&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I subject my wife to one of the stranger drinks, "&lt;strong&gt;Follow That Black Rabbit&lt;/strong&gt;".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a shaker:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.75 oz OJ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.75 oz maple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.75 oz gin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.75 oz Fernet Branca&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5 oz lemon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shake with ice, pour to a highball with ice, garnish w orange twist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-06-03-Covid-cocktails-8/follow-that-black-rabbit.jpg" alt="Follow That Black Rabbit" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh wow this is a complex drink.  The Fernet and orange and maple attack your mouth in three different places at once.  At the same time, it's sweet enough to be kinda approachable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"So, honey, do you like it?"&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;"It's weird."&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;"Good weird or bad weird?"&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;"Uh... I don't know."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: The Educated Barfly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://theeducatedbarfly.com/follow-that-black-rabbit/"&gt;https://theeducatedbarfly.com/follow-that-black-rabbit/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, my pic above was bad because I was so excited to try this strange drink that I took a few sips before taking the photo and then handing it off to my wife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pull in a slightly unorthodox ingredient for the &lt;strong&gt;Breakfast Martini&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a shaker, add:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 heaping tsp orange marmalade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.66 oz gin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5 oz triple sec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5 oz lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shake, double-strain to chilled cocktail glass.
Garnish with orange twist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-06-03-Covid-cocktails-8/breakfast-martini.jpg" alt="Breakfast Martini" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orange. Boozey orange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a sour aftertaste. The Cointreau and marmalade make it pleasantly sweet and with a strong orange flavor halfway between fruit juice and syrupy orange freezies, with a botanical undercurrent.  Then the lemon hits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy and straightforward sweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little bit of wine crime.  This one's barely a cocktail, the &lt;strong&gt;Kir&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just mix in glass&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 oz white wine (I'm using Pinot Grigio + Chardonnay)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.25 oz creme de cassis...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my cassis has a pretty weak flavor so I bumped it up to 0.66 oz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-06-03-Covid-cocktails-8/kir.jpg" alt="kir" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, it turned a dry-ish white wine into something a bit more dessert-y.  The cassis adds a little sugar, body and fruitiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not much to it but that's what you'd expect from a simple 2-ingredient drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those keeping score, this is my 100th distinct cocktail since I started mixing a year ago!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCioZY1p0bZ4Xt-yodw8_cBQ"&gt;How To Drink&lt;/a&gt; vids got me into this, I decided it would be good to mix one of the first h2d originals: the &lt;strong&gt;Gin Whisper&lt;/strong&gt; for the Centennial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a shaker, muddle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 mint leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then add&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.25 oz simple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.25 oz St Germain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 oz gin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one egg white&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I like to steep the mint in the simple syrup for a minute while I gather ingredients)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dry shake, then shake with ice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Double strain to glass, garnish w mint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-06-03-Covid-cocktails-8/gin-whisper.jpg" alt="gin whisper" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked this.  Creamy, sweet, and intricate.  A bit of a bitter undercurrent from its booziness and the botanicals, but it starts with the mint and elderflower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm surprised I could get a decent egg foam without acid from citrus fruit - afaik the acid causes the egg to foam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I hate shaken mint.  The ice pulverizes it so a few flakes always come through the strainer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Relevant How to Drink Vid&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rO3zlIPJTYI" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New ingredient!  I broke the bank and bought some artisanal rum from Halifax (!).  Compass Distillers' Daily Ration rum.  I'm combining that with How To Drink's &lt;strong&gt;Rum Old Fashioned&lt;/strong&gt; recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a rocks glass:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 thin (1/8" thick or less) slices of lime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 bar-spoons demerara syrup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 dashes of angostura bitters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then muddle, and add&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 oz rum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 block of ice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-06-03-Covid-cocktails-8/rum-old-fashioned.jpg" alt="rum old fashioned" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's good.  Lime forward with a rum funk and the angostura spice undercurrent.  Refreshing despite its booziness.  It straddles the line between a daiquiri and an old fashioned.  A good drink for when you want something stiff but also it's summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Relevant How To Drink vid&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Zuj8AuVWKx4" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 8, Drink 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm flying out Monday so I'm rushing out the last few cocktails to finish out the set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, day 8, drink 1 of 2: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;East India No. 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In mixing glass w ice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.66oz brandy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.33oz triple sec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5oz pineapple juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 barspoon simple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mix, strain to glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-06-03-Covid-cocktails-8/East-India-no-3.jpg" alt="East India no 3" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;... tastes like Pineapple and brandy.  Which, all things considered, isn't bad.  Kind of sweet and boozy.  It's nice, but a bit one-note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wife approved - which is funny, she was apprehensive about brandy when I bought it, but likes all the brandy drinks I mixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 8, Drink 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another wine crime called an &lt;strong&gt;Elderflower Spritz&lt;/strong&gt;.  This calls for sauv blanc but I'm cheating and using a pinot grigio + chardonnay mix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build in a glass full of ice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 oz white wine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 oz St. Germain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 oz club soda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Garnish w lime&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-06-03-Covid-cocktails-8/elderflower-spritz.jpg" alt="elderflower spritz" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, this is a super simple cocktail but I really liked it.  St Germain has a sort of sweet but acidic and floral stonefruity flavor to it - like a gourmet take on sour candy.  That's flavors you get naturally in some white wines but turned up to 11.  So mixing it with the pinot grigio/chardonnay mix works really well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result reminds me of a particularly good Vidal late harvest icewine I once had, but lengthened and fizzy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 9, Drink 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn't get around to taking my morning coffee until after noon today. Which means it's time to spike it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I don't have cream, or Grand Marnier (orange brandy), but I decided to make a Mexicano coffee anyways, or at least an approximation thereof. Let's call this a &lt;strong&gt;Mexicano con Leche&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a Toddy glass:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz blanco tequila&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.25 oz Cointreau&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.25 oz brandy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 bar-spoons demerara syrup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stir...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;coffee to near the top&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Top with foamed hot milk, fresh nutmeg, and cocoa powder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-06-03-Covid-cocktails-8/Mexicano-con-leche.jpg" alt="Mexicano con leche" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nice.  A bit mild because of the substitutions.  First sip is especially nice with the cocoa and nutmeg nose, then you get into it with the coffee with a nice hint of brandy and orange.  I wish I still had a reposado, a more flavorful tequila would've been better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 9, Drink 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Black Eyed Susan&lt;/strong&gt;.  No, not the 12-bottle-bar Black Eyed Susan I made before, this is the one they currently serve at Preakness Stakes.  The cocktail changes &lt;em&gt;drastically&lt;/em&gt; over the years, but this is the current standard (except I'm mixing the sour mix from scratch instead of pre-made).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making it mostly because I picked up some peach schnapps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a shaker, add&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz vodka&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz bourbon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz peach schnapps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 oz OJ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.66 oz simple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5 oz lemon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5 oz lime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shake with ice, double-strain to an ice-filled glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Garnish with cherry and orange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-06-03-Covid-cocktails-8/black-eyed-Susan.jpg" alt="Black Eyed Susan" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;... it's sweet.  And peachy.  And sweet.  And boozy.  The boozy flavor works with it but yeah it's really sweet. Probably wouldn't hurt to cut back the syrup - I was trying to approximate 2 oz sour mix with the sugar and lemon and lime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy to drink and can get you in trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 9, Drink 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, I gave wifey the Black Eyed Susan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made myself Erick Castro's "&lt;strong&gt;Kentucky Buck&lt;/strong&gt;", which is a nice summer ginger drink.  Although I don't have ginger syrup so I'm going to follow a redditor's version and use Ginger Beer instead of ginger syrup and club soda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a shaker:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 strawberry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 dashes angostura&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5 oz simple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.75 oz lemon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 oz bourbon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shake with ice, then add&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 oz ginger beer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then double-strain to a Collins glass full of ice.  Garnish with lemon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-06-03-Covid-cocktails-8/Kentucky-buck.jpg" alt="Kentucky Buck" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn't need the simple syrup, the ginger beer brings enough sweetness.  I think the simple came from the Reddit substitution, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lemon subdues the ginger beer a bit so it doesn't bite as much.  Very refreshing.  The strawberry is a bit too subtle, but I wouldn't want a second berry in there for the strainer.  I like how the bourbon flavors aren't lost... they still come through nicely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all I'm not sure who this is for.  I prefer the Dark n Stormy, but you have to really love ginger beer for that... But if you don't love ginger beer I'm not sure this will do it for you either.  I just feel like the rum funk goes better with ginger beer flavors than bourbon and lemon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 10, Drink 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a bottle of Rumchata for coffee, and googled a random cocktail to mix with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://mantitlement.com/rumchata-double-chocolate-aperitif&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, "RumChata &lt;strong&gt;Double Chocolate Aperitif&lt;/strong&gt; will be the only thing your guests will want after dinner"... already a great start 🤨.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a shaker, mix:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 oz Rumchata&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz 360 double chocolate vodka&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5 oz chocolate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5 Kahlua&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rim a glass with chocolate sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mix with ice in the shaker (don't shake?  I'll just use a mixing glass then).  Strain to glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Garnish w mint and cherry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-06-03-Covid-cocktails-8/RumChata-double-chocolate-aperitif.jpg" alt="RumChata Double Chocolate Apertif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wowww too sweet.  It's basically a liquified slice of coffee cake.  Which, if that's what you're into have at it.  I added ice to chill it and lengthen it a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd garnish it with one of those skinny sandwich biscuits or a cake-pop or something instead of mint.  Dunk!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 10, Drink 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr Bali Hai&lt;/strong&gt;.  A nice tiki drink with a coffee twist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 oz Jamaican-style rum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz light rum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.75 oz kahlua&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 oz pineapple juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 oz lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.25 oz simple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shake w ice, double strain to a glass of crushed ice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, I cheated, I didn't use crushed ice, just regular ice cubes.  It was late and I didn't want to make noise crushing ice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Garnish with mint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pxtl.ca/images/2023-06-03-Covid-cocktails-8/mr-bali-hai.jpg" alt="Mr Bali Hai" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a good one.  Interesting drink with a surprising mix of fruit and coffee flavors.  It's such a strange fusion that my wife started thinking "caramel?" from the color.  Approachable, surprising, and fun.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bit sweet - enthusiasts recommend Mr Black over Kahlua for that.  Definitely doesn't need the syrup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with that, I'm done another 14 drinks, this time in only 10 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel silly writing this almost two years later, but life happens.  Since this project I got the unfortunate talking-to from my doctor about blood sugar - diabetes sucks.  So cocktails are now a once-a-week treat for me, and often involve diet sodas.  Maybe someday I'll put together an article of my favorite "diet" cocktails.  Yes, I know alcohol gets metabolized into sugar, so yeah still gotta go easy on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the cocktails I made in this sprint, the one that sticks in my memory is the &lt;strong&gt;Follow That Black Rabbit&lt;/strong&gt;.  That drink was a journey.  But reading my old notes and the &lt;strong&gt;Elderflower Spritz&lt;/strong&gt; is definitely coming back to me as a good one.&lt;/p&gt;
</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pxtl.ca/2022/11/24/birdsite/</guid><link>http://www.pxtl.ca/2022/11/24/birdsite/</link><author>pxtl@hotmail.com</author><category>Politics</category><title>Birdsite</title><description>&lt;p&gt;On the birdsite: Musk's policy changes were about "Free Speech"... but it's
become extremely clear that the particular speech he was focused on liberating
was transphobia.  Most of the accounts he unbanned were banned for anti-trans
hate-speech, and he's since gotten very chummy with notorious anti-trans
extremists on Twitter. He's also tweeted anti-trans stuff himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's hard to avoid that detail -- when he says he bought twitter for "free
speech", its important to ask "about what?".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 05:00:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2022-11-24T05:00:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the birdsite: Musk's policy changes were about "Free Speech"... but it's
become extremely clear that the particular speech he was focused on liberating
was transphobia.  Most of the accounts he unbanned were banned for anti-trans
hate-speech, and he's since gotten very chummy with notorious anti-trans
extremists on Twitter. He's also tweeted anti-trans stuff himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's hard to avoid that detail -- when he says he bought twitter for "free
speech", its important to ask "about what?".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a person with trans family, this is a deal-breaker for me, and I'd hope for
many others.  Many artists I follow have exited for the same reason, often in
spectacularly pyrotechnic fashions, &lt;a href="https://www.cbc.ca/radio/day6/elon-musk-twitter-impersonations-1.6648071"&gt;such as the QuestionableContent comic artist
Jeph Jacques&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I'm really hoping this Mastodon thing takes off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know some people are going to other social networks like Tumblr, Hive, and
Post.... but fundamentally, what's to stop their owners from ruining those sites
too? Tumblr in particular already had an exodus because of bad moderation once
before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People have complained that Mastodon's governance model is like an HOA. Each
server is a private nation with complicated political relationships to other
servers. That's bad... but is a new hopefully-benevolent dictator better?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mastodon is flawed.  It's confusing, it's overloaded, and it's questionable how
fiscally sound its servers are.  But Twitter's Muskpocalypse has proven how
governance is important.  And Mastodon gives people the tools to care about
governance.  We can emigrate to new servers. We can build our own servers that
can be run as we see fit.  We can modify the code of our server. Nobody &lt;em&gt;owns&lt;/em&gt;
the Fediverse network Mastodon's servers run on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Twitter's moderation matters, then ownership matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm at &lt;a href="https://mastodon.social/@Pxtl"&gt;@Pxtl@Mastodon.Social&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pxtl.ca/2022/05/18/alcohol-in-parks/</guid><link>http://www.pxtl.ca/2022/05/18/alcohol-in-parks/</link><author>pxtl@hotmail.com</author><category>HamOnt</category><title>Alcohol in parks letter</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Text of an email I sent to council today, after they discovered we don't have an "alcohol in parks bylaw" and Ward 8 councilor JP Danko motioned looking into responsible ways to allow it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 04:00:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2022-05-18T04:00:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Text of an email I sent to council today, after they discovered we don't have an "alcohol in parks bylaw" and Ward 8 councilor JP Danko motioned looking into responsible ways to allow it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Councilor Wilson, Councilor Danko, Mr Mayor,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm writing to voice my support for opening up Hamilton city parks to drinking, and to thank councilor Danko for opening this subject up for study. I think we should be collectively ashamed that we didn't properly move on this in 2020 when COVID shutdown orders effectively declared that anybody who didn't have access to a private yard was effectively banned from socializing over drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ontario's puritanical attitude towards drinking only seems normal to people who don't travel enough to see other places where enjoying a drink out in public is normal and fine. It's time to begin relaxing these rules and allowing responsible consumption.  The Quebec approach (with a meal, daytime-only) seems perfectly reasonable, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to those who worry about garbage: picnics also cause garbage. Sports events cause garbage. &lt;em&gt;Use&lt;/em&gt; causes garbage. Too many people see the city's parks as extensions of their private gardens, meant only to be observed. Parks were meant to be enjoyed, and this program would offer a new way to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your time,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin Zarate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ward 1 resident&lt;/p&gt;
</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pxtl.ca/2021/09/10/political-abbreviations/</guid><link>http://www.pxtl.ca/2021/09/10/political-abbreviations/</link><author>pxtl@hotmail.com</author><category>Politics</category><title>2021 election leader abbreviations</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Review of abbreviations people use when writing about the leaders on Twitter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JT&lt;/strong&gt;: Sounds like an 18-year-old played by a 27-year-old in a prime-time soap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EOT&lt;/strong&gt;: ASCII char 04, End Of Transmission&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YFB&lt;/strong&gt;: Which airport is that again?  Oh, right, Iqaluit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Singh &amp;amp; Paul&lt;/strong&gt;: Short last names means no fun abbrevs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 04:00:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2021-09-10T04:00:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Review of abbreviations people use when writing about the leaders on Twitter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JT&lt;/strong&gt;: Sounds like an 18-year-old played by a 27-year-old in a prime-time soap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EOT&lt;/strong&gt;: ASCII char 04, End Of Transmission&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YFB&lt;/strong&gt;: Which airport is that again?  Oh, right, Iqaluit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Singh &amp;amp; Paul&lt;/strong&gt;: Short last names means no fun abbrevs.&lt;/p&gt;
</a10:content></item></channel></rss>